<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="vitek_voron_name"><text>Vityok Raven</text></string>
<string id="artem_kulinar_name"><text>Artyom Cook</text></string>
<string id="mil_lukash_healing_armor_01"><text>You made me happy, Marked One! Military had a great suit, we'll try to adopt their fabric impregnation trick into our suit designs. And we'll give you certain recipes as a reward. We have our own genius here. Chef's the name. Maybe you already met him, he managed to make new artifacts from a simple Droplet. Alright, I'll leave you to the recipe. Don't be surprised at the names - Chef became a deeply poetic person after being hit in the head. Have some understanding, would you?</text></string>
<string id="mil_lukash_healing_armor_02"><text>Sure, no need to even ask.</text></string>
<string id="mil_lukash_healing_armor_03"><text>One more thing, Marked One. I'm expecting that those who like to inflict good, the ones from Duty, won't learn this recipe.</text></string>
<string id="mil_lukash_healing_armor_04"><text>I can guarantee that.</text></string>

<string id="trader_beads_1"><text>And apart from all this stuff I gave you, take this recipe on how to transmute one artifact into another one. Yes, you heard me right, it can be done. Why are you looking at me like an innocent child? Get your PDA, I'll drop you the info.</text></string>

<string id="trader_beads_2"><text>I think it's pointless asking where you got that kind of information?</text></string>

<string id="trader_beads_3"><text>Yeah. Perhaps you’d also like the key of the apartment where the money is? Haha, where do you get ideas like this? Stop staring blankly at me and get your PDA.</text></string>

<string id="ecolog_prizrak_outfit_reward_1"><text>We'd like to thank you for the suit in particular, it's crucially important to our research. If you'd be so kind, get your PDA ready. I assure you that the information about this hyper-modificate, which I will upload to it, is extremely valuable. "Chimera's tears" will not just help you to resist controller attacks, but also possibly to get into Pripyat! Although it's only a conjecture. Here, the upload is ready! We hope for a long and productive cooperation, Marked One.</text></string>

<string id="drunk_dolg_reward_phr_1"><text>You know, stalker, we have a saying: "Duty" never stays in debt. Take a recipe on how to make an upgrate to a certain artifact. Trust me, it's a valuable information. Use it at your discretion.</text></string>

<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_1"><text>Thanks, friend! You saved me, I have no words. If we'll both get through this and will cross our ways - I'll try to repay you. But now I can only share some useful information. There's a farm occupied by free stalkers, south from here. So, one of them is selling a gauss rifle for cheap, just eight hundred. I was going to buy it myself and here I go, caught in this turmoil... So if you have money, go ahead. Sorry, I can't give you anything useful besides this info. Although... Ever heard anything about the "Snotty Porcupine"?</text></string>
<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_2"><text>Must be an amusing creature...</text></string>
<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_3"><text>Yeah no, that's a transmuted artifact! It's got a peculiar name because it's oozing with some smelling slime, so intensely that you'd better not put it in a pouch or onto your belt - impossible to wash your pants out of this stuff! It's better to keep it in a waterproof bag, or even better in a sealed plastic container. Well, I think you'll sort it out, if you manage to transmute it.</text></string>
<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_4"><text>Where did you get that recipe, huh? You seem like a newbie in the Zone...</text></string>
<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_5"><text>What, is it really so obvious? And this... I stumpled upon a dead Duty guy, don't think it was me, I had zero chance with my sawn off against his exosuit and Val! Something mighty killed him - his exosuit looked like it's been chewn and spat out. His gun was a sorry sight. His PDA fell out from either his backpack or a pocket. So, I found there a recipe from the scientists, they are buddies with Duty, as it's apparent from the note. You can read it yourself, after all!</text></string>
<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_6"><text>Well, thank you! Good luck!</text></string>


<string id="amk_zapiska"><text>Piece of paper covered with notes</text></string>

<string id="amk_zapiska_s"><text>Note</text></string>

<string id="mil_freedom_commander_3001_amk"><text>Thanks Marked One, you've helped us out. My guys are exhausted - a couple hours ago a controller with his escort of boars and snorks. We barely warded them off, three of my guys fell, and the others got it in the brain from a controller, my head still feels leaden. You could have told that by our accuracy - we were shooting precisely but in a wrong direction... Controller went away, that son of a bitch... But enough with it. I want to give you a recipe for your timely help. We've had Grisha Sound getting back out of a raid, there was a harsh incident happening to his squad... So, he killed some Dutyers; and one of them had a useful info with a note from the scientists. You'll get it yourself as you read it. Take care! Hope we meet again.</text></string>
  
<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_rg6_finish_1_amk"><text>Good job, stalker. That's exactly what we needed. You carried out my request, Marked One, and you can have this suit, I think you'll like it... One more thing, Marked One. The scientists gave us a recipe, just as old friends. As an appreciation for our service, so to speak. I see you're a reasonable man, and I think you'll find yourself in our ranks soon... Get your PDA, brother, I'll upload a file onto it.</text></string>
  
<string id="amk_hud_disabled"><text>Interactive HUD off</text></string>
<string id="amk_hud_enabled"><text>Interactive HUD on</text></string>
<string id="amk_hud_and_steam_enabled"><text>Interactive HUD on + breathing effect</text></string>
  
<string id="amk_mat_disabled"><text>Swearing in the news off</text></string>
<string id="amk_mat_enabled"><text>Swearing in the news on</text></string>
  
<string id="amk_rad_disabled"><text>Radiation meter off</text></string>
<string id="amk_rad_enabled"><text>Radiation meter on</text></string>
  
<string id="amk_mus_disabled"><text>Dynamic soundtrack off</text></string>
<string id="amk_mus_enabled"><text>Dynamic soundtrack on</text></string>
  
<string id="amk_treasure_old"><text>Classic stashes</text></string>
<string id="amk_treasure_new"><text>Random stashes</text></string>
<string id="amk_treasure_rare"><text>Rare stashes</text></string>

<string id="amk_options"><text>AMK options</text></string>
    
<string id="amk_rkd0"><text>Hello.</text></string>
  
<string id="amk_rkd1"><text>Hey guy, I have two news for you: a good one and a bad one. I'll start with a bad one. No idea what have you got into, but you surely did - I've been sent to kill you.</text></string>
  
<string id="amk_rkd2"><text>...?!</text></string>
  
<string id="amk_rkd3"><text>And a good one - I'm very reluctant to do it. Why? I don't know myself. But you have a great chance to save your ass. But you know, nothing in this life comes for free.</text></string>
<string id="amk_rkd4"><text>Screw you!</text></string>
<string id="amk_rkd5"><text>You know, Marked One, I knew it'd come to that sooner or later...</text></string>
<string id="amk_rkd6"><text>So decide for yourself, guy...</text></string>
<string id="amk_rkd8"><text>Be glad I'm in a good mood today, guy.</text></string>
  
<string id="amk_recipt_stone_dikoobraz_1_text"><text>Record 1: "... meanwhile, we've seen the whole process from start to finish, despite that the Monolith soldiers encircled the "Springboard", trying to hide the artifact and the transmutation process from a possible surveillance. But Artyom got himself an advantageous vantage point and he managed to have a look at the artifact they threw into the anomaly. It turned out to be a "Snotty Porcupine" (the name is weird, but a genuine one, given by a stalker who discovered it; we checked it). After an hour and a half, towards the evening, the anomaly spat the artifact back out. We need to get it back from the Monolithians now. Artyom suggested to do it during their next prayer, which will start 40 minutes from now. I'd like to put a word for this smart guy when we're back. Vladislav Leonidovich, I hope you'll support me..." \n \nRecord 2: "...I'll put the data fragments onto an USB drive, making a backup copy. We dealt with the Monolithians quite quickly, while they were doing some bizarre ritual around a black block someone of them brought in his backpack (I thought it was a backpack at first, but then it turned out to be a portable altar(!); Vladislav Leonidovich, I think that observation wil be interesting to both our Russian and foreign colleagues). Artyom opened fire with his Vintorez, and I've supported him by throwing two grenades. Our fears didn't come true - the artifact remained unscathed, to our delight. After two days into our raid, I observed the following properties in the "Stone Porcupine" (we gave the name due to its Snotty Porcupine origin): this artifact, which I'd classify as absolute, lowers the absorbed radiation dose by 50 ?R/h! Apart from this rarest property, the "Stone Porcupine" makes its bearer less suspectible to blasts and shock waves, stops bleeding efficiently, and makes you jump higher..." \n \nRecord 3: We're being followed. Monolithians, about 15 people. We tried to lose them and failed. They are trying to encircle us slowly. I'll leave the USB drive with the backup to Artyom Inkin, and try to hold them back..."</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_stone_dikoobraz_2_text"><text>Record 1: "... they took me at the village exit... I've killed five of them... we didn't even have the time to send our coordinates, the evac squad is still waiting... Andrey Semyonovich got his leg blown off below the ankle, goddamn! They led us for a long time, I've been carrying wounded Andrey Semyonovich. I didn't even know they got an underground shelter here. These brutes told us they'll avenge their brothers' deaths. They threw Andrey Semyonovich into the next cell, he was unconscious already... they untied my hands and didn't even take my backpack and PDA, only the gun and the ammo..."\n \nRecord 2: "... I don't know what it is... I don't know... It's not a chimera, not a bloodsucker... It's not a... It crawled out of the hole to their chanting! They opened the door to the Andrey Semyonovich's cell... It didn't touch them, it went right to the cell... it crawled into it... and... AND STARTED TO DEVOUR HIM! HE WAS STILL ALIVE AND CRIED!!! IT GNAWED HIS FACE WHILE HE CROAKED AND TRIED TO... WITH HIS HANDS..." \n \nRecord 3: "... it will come back... Monolithians went away, it's sitting there in the hole... I can hear it thinking. They went away and opened the door to my cell... it climbed down into the hole and speaks to me from there and... and Andrey Semyonovich speaks to me too... in my head. I'll go away... I'll just take Andrey Semyonovich's hand with me... he tells me that even his hand will be enough... it's... it's important, very important... and it doesn't come out... it's glowing down in the hole... like a rainbow... and tells me not to go anywhere... but I will go... they didn't even lock the door... they said it won't let me to crawl out... but it went back into the hole once it eat Andrey Semyonovich... it only left his hand... Andrey Semyonovich tell me to leave now... while it's thinking in its hole... And to take his hand with me... because it's very important to him..." \n \nRecord 4: "I deceived it... it's dumb... I took Andrey Semenovich's hand and my backpack... and went away. It started roaring and crawling out... but stopped suddenly - I told it that I need to go. It beleived me and didn't follow me! Just roared for a long time and glowed in the dark... I TRICKED IT! I tricked it...</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_steel_kolobok_text"><text>Record 1: "Found a dead stalker, or at least what remained of him, next to a "Springboard". He had a "Kolobok" in his backpack, but a weird one - it's glowing. I've brainstormed it a bit and decided to throw this "Kolobok" into the "Springborad" and look what will happen. Could have made some booze for it, but... but whatever, I'll just try it." \n \nRecord 2: "I'm waiting for forty minutes already. Killed a lone zombie. It was a mistake to feed the anomaly with this "Kolobok", I should have known better!" \n \nRecord 3: "Gotcha! The anomaly fired it like a cork out of a bottle! An hour has passed, and here it is. It's glowing! I have to drink to it!" \n \nRecord 4: "Phew! I got lucky! Now I'll be always walk around the Zone drunk, because I'd surely die if I was sober! I've encountered a bandit. He shot me with his PM, but it got jammed immediately. This son of a bitch took out the knife and stabbed me with it. I killed this asshole with my double barrel!" \n \nRecord 5: "It's not that simple. Something isn't right. For example, I remember how he ripped my jacket open with a knife, I surely do. I remember the stab, but I only have a scratch on my belly. Maybe my "Koloboks" helped me out? "Steel Koloboks"... Hell, and these little balls are also glowing. Yeah, I think "Balls of Steel" would have been better..."</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_titan_kolobok_text"><text>Saracen dragged in some newbie he caught. Told us that he didn't kill him on sight because the newbie was glancing left and right and looked suspisious, like he was carrying something valuable. A stubborn milk-drinker! We found an uncommon "Kolobok" in his backpack. Well... it looked like a "Kolobok" it wasn't one. We asked him what's that thing he was carrying, but he's been silent like a rock. I can respect that! He certainly didn't look tough! Swede broke a couple of his fingers before the newbie told us everything. Told us that it's a "Steel Kolobok" transmuted in a "Whirlgig". Threwn into it for an hour and became a different artifact. Told us that is keeps you safe from punches, and is effective against cuts, but damn, it's radioactive and you'd better not get caught into a "Matrix" with it. He got it a cool name - "Titanium Kolobok"! We should check if that dupe told us the truth. I'd also like to find a "Steel Kolobok"...</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_almaz_kolobok_text"><text>This hyper-modificate, obtained through the transmutation of the "Titanium Kolobok" meso-modificate in a "Fruit Punch" anomaly, makes the bearer's sking resistant to cuts and punches. The downside is that this hyper-modificate is radioactive.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_controller_skalp_text"><text>May He ascend to Eternity! May He change the World! \n \nOur Mentor, Victor, has announced the success of his naturalists! The Mentor believes, like all of us, that He has bestowed upon us, His followers, with a gift to strengthen our faith! Following a battle with a military detachment, which guarded the scientists, the leader of the phalanx, Ostach, brought the "Armor", along with bodies and trophies. Along with the bodies of the Lost, it was sacrificed to His Flame and the Trackers, brother Akim and brother Leho, found the "Armor", which fell out of the "Flame" about an hour and a half later. It glowed unusually, which the Trackers understood as His sign. This altered "Armor" was carried by the naturalist brother Roman into two later battles. On the way back, his phalanx battled four burers in the Catacombs. Brother Roman claimed that this altered "Armor" worked wonders - he could not feel the psy-attacks from the burers! He also noticed, that while wearing this artifact, he felt no hunger. Truly, He still gifts us pieces of Eternity! Further natural experiments have shown, that this artifact, named after it's qualities as "Controller's scalp", improves well-being, stops bleeding and protects against chemical burns. Our faith grows and grows stronger day by day! For He remembers us! May He live for Eternity! May He change the World!</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_souls_text"><text>... So this is how it was. July 7th, at night, half a month ago, in the building #3, a "Ravenous Bear" has emerged, which is just a roaming "Burner" anomaly. I've been alone in this building, Max and Yurka Sevastopol left, however I still wonder when did they leave... we drank like crazy. I was going to drop a bedroll in a corner, and suddenly a fire plume gushed from a wall! I was drunk, and at first I thought that Timur Marinade got that military flamethrower we found working, and is having fun with it. Then I thought a gas pipeline broke - there was a kitchen behind that wall once. Then I recalled that the gas supply had been cut off for about fifteen years here, wasn't sure what to do, and started to pour water over it. But when I saw the fire crawling over a wall, I got it, but it was too late - I managed to pull my G36 off the peg, but lost my backpack with a "Soul" I've found two days ago. I felt upset and drank some more. And after an hour and a half I see my "Soul" dropping out of the flames! It was glowing funny, like a lamp. I grabbed it and put into a container. When I woke up next morning, I saw the guys roasting a boar at the "Burner". I immediately remembered my "Soul". Told Max I'm leaving and went off to the eggheads. The way was full of fun, but that's another story. Got there, gave this "Soul" for the analysis. Sakharov has been scratching his bald head for a while after seeing this. "This artifact, apart from improving bearer's health, - he said, - gained the ability to lower the absorbed dose". This artifact (I called it "Soul Droplet", a cool name) also causes you to tire faster. Sakharov tried for a while to talk me into selling it, but I didn't fall for it. I already had a plan to throw this artifact into a "Burner" and see what happens, and then bring it to Sakharov for the analysis. He scratched his skull again, and agreed. I took my "Soul Droplet" and came into the tunnel. There are lots of "Burners" here. Threw it and waited a bit. After an hour it appeared, but was reluctant to drop out of the anomaly. I barely got it out, burned myself, and almost lost my hair like Sakharov. Brought it for analysis and proved myself right! This artifact (I called it "Fiery Soul") is protecting from the radiation two times better! I regret not joining a university. I could have been a scientist or some kind of professor... So, I went to a "Burner" the third time, like a damn Fisherman to the Golden Fish. Dropped a couple zombified stalkers on my way there, one of them turned out to be Mikha Cameroon, I drank to his peace later. So this was his destiny, I drank with him just a month ago, and today I put a bullet into his head... rest in peace... I threw the "Fiery Soul" into the "Burner" and waited again. After an hour and a half it popped out, good thing I didn't have to poke the anomaly this time. I even managed to nap while it was there... It's glowing happily. I took the artifact and went to the eggheads. A whole team of them had been waiting for me there, they offered me some coffee and brandy while being busy with the artifact. Being in a high mood after the Hennessy and coffee, I thought up a name for it - "Crystal Soul". Eggheads were ecstatic about the artifact, told me that it's a hyp... hyperdif... I mean, "Crystal Soul" improves your health, and it's got huge radiation protection capabilities as well. The next morning I went to the "Burner" again and dropped my precious "Crystal Soul" into it. Waited for a long time and saw it popping back out. The glow didn't change a bit. To hell with it, I thought. Was just heading back as I saw a roaming "Electra" in the underpass blocking my way. I sat there thinking, what if I drop my artifact into it! It turned out to be working like a "Burner" - the artifact disappeared into it and popped back out in just an hour. It was glowing entirely different! I waited for the Electra to move out of my way, and went to Yantar with my "Soul". Sakharov disappeared with it in his lab for a long time, and when he walked out, his eyes were shining behind his glasses like he was a psycho. He told me it's some kind of an absolute. The trans... transm... I mean, altered "Soul" made you tired faster, and this one increases your stamina. I made some mighty buck for letting the eggheads study my "Soul"...</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_electra_text"><text>The "Moonlight" artifact is placed into an "Electra" anomaly. The "Electra's Tears" artifact, which is a result of this transmutation, increases bearer's stamina. It also has a negative impact over a human organism, making it susceptible to cuts and bruises.\nNote: only a "Moonlight" with positive properties can be used in the recipe!</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_fire_text"><text>The "Electra's Tears" modificate is dropped into a "Burner" anomaly. The "Fire Tears" meso-modificate, which is a result of this transmutation, greatly increases bearer's stamina, and protects the bearer from fire. Cuts and bruises suspectibility.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_chimaera_text"><text>The "Fire Tears" meso-modificate is placed into a "Fruit Punch" anomaly. The resulting "Chimera's Tears" hyper-modificate greatly increases bearer's stamina, and also protects its bearer from fire and electricity.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_gigant_text"><text>The "Chimera's Tears" hyper-modificate is placed into an "Electra" anomaly. The resulting absolute greatly increases bearer's stamina, and blocks almost a half of fire and electricity damage as well.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>For obligatory acquaintance. \n \nSoldiers! Our comrades, the scientists, gave us the information about the possibility of alteration of the "Mama's Beads" artifact with the subsequent obtaining of the new properties as a result. The artifact in question is only susceptible to alteration in an "Electra" anomaly, in which it needs to be put into for one hour. After that, it obtains the new properties with high probability. I'll cite a scientific document: "The resulting modificate produces a temporal field which reduces the velocity of the bullets hitting it, protecting the person from fatal wounds as a result. When worn at the belt, it's possible to carry large weights. It's a bit radioactive." \n \nI'd recommend you to copy the file into your PDAs, and give this information to any squad leaders you encounter in a raid.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>... I've found Vanka Four Fingers in a village, where I was trying to hide from a pack of dogs. I was laying low in a house basement as I've heard a Geiger counter clicking outside. I've grabbed my gun immediately: it could have been a bandit or a merc. I've peeped out of the hatch, and saw him lying face-down in a "Fruit Punch". I've only recognized him by his stupid red bandana with the hammer and sickle coat of arms. Not even four hours have passed as we parted our ways; he went ahead, and I stayed waiting for Vadik Blush, to hand him a package. Damn, what a disappointment... Well, I put my gas mask on and dragged his body out of the anomaly. I couldn't understand how he got there, he was roaming the Zone for more than three years, when I saw that his neck is broken. I immediately changed my mind about the proper burial, of course. Who knows what kind of housekeeper was marinating stalkers here, or even grazing nearby. I've looted him quickly trying not to touch his clothing, took off his backpack and his artifacts from the belt. Didn't take his favorite TOZ as the "Fruit Punch" ate most of it. And then I skipped out of there as quick as possible. Vanka only had three artifacts with him. "Droplet", "Sea Urchin", and these "Grandmother's Beads" of his. "Droplet" and "Sea Urchin" were hanging from the back on his belt, and the "Grandmother's Beads" got into the anomaly. I thought the artifact was done for, but it turned out it isn't just intact, but also has an amazing glow. I've tested it a bit on my way to Freedom. It changed! I called it a "Great Grandmother's Beads". It protected me from the bullets well, when I've encountered a zombified military. And my backpack got lighter somehow. It also seems to be less radioactive than the "Grandmother's Beads". I'll probably sell it to the scientists, and buy myself some new equipment.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_burer_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>Record: "I have some information for you. You know, I served as a secretary at our base: worked with a PC, taking care of the reports and documents. And then, when you stalkers were being killed every day by our guys, I decided I've had enough! Anyway, not the point. I've read some file accidentally... well, maybe it wasn't by accident... So it took a lot of time to make the code out, until I hacked it... I didn't copy it, but remembered it well. It was a report from the eggheads on artifact alteration in anomalies. Can you imagine that! It was written in the report that if you take a me... meso something... called "Great Grandmother's Beads" - a dumb name, I remembered it immediately, don't ask me what it is, I have no idea - and put it into a "Whirlgig", you will get another artifact after an hour and a half, if I remember it right! Well, not another one.... it's the same one, but with different properties. It radiates some field around it, so anything flying into it gets slowed. I think it means bullets! It also allows you to carry additional weight. Here, I think this information will help you more than me.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_burer_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>"Burer Grandmother's Beads" hyper-modificate is placed into a "Burner" anomaly. The resulting absolute greatly increases bearer's stamina, partially blocks the telepathic effect, and allows the bearer to carry more weight.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_dikoobraz_text"><text>... to make the transmutation, the "Sea Urchin" artifact with just the positive properties is placed into a "Burner" anomaly. After an hour, if the transmutation succeeds, it obtains a very good radiation resistance property. It also has a negative effect on the bearer's stamina and blood coagulation. The subsequent experiments showed that the resulting "Porcupine" artifact isn't able to be transmuted further in this anomaly.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_electra_dikoobraz_text"><text>For internal use by Freedom members only! Top fucking secret! \n \nVityok Blush managed to create a new artifact! You need a "Porcupine" as a source, throw it into an "Electra" and this artifact will hatch from it after an hour. Blush called it the "Electric Porcupine", but who cares anyway. What matters is that artifact holds the radiation back well, and helps against "Electras". Sluggish, before you ask about girls, go bother people at the forums with that. Don't try PMing me, I'll fucking murder you. Oh, and a warning to everyone! You get tired faster with this "Electric Porcupine" at your belt, and make sure to shave carefully to not get cut. Take care! \n \nStepan Mediacenter, public relations.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_sopl_dikoobraz_text"><text>Gentlemen! The group of Mr. Alexey Astronomer did us an invaluable service. The territory around our field laboratory has been flooded with boars and fleshes. It's their second migration wave after a recent blowout, and we already had injuries among our personnel. The group of Mr. Alexey Astronomer came to our call for help and completely wiped the mutants out. We think that a simple monetary reward doesn't represent our deep appreciation, and send you the information on how to make a hyper-modificate called "Snotty Porcupine". Sorry for a vulgar name, but it was given by a creator of this hyper-modificate and describes its nature perfectly. I hope that Duty soldiers have a sense of humour and react to this name appropriately. To make a "Snotty Porcupine" you have to place an "Electric Porcupine" artifact into a "Fruit Punch" anomaly for a half and an hour. I want to mention the radiation blocking property of this artifact - a human only receives 35 percent of the dose they would get without this hyper-modificate. Apart from this, it's also very effective at stopping the bleeding, and mitigates chemical burns. An unpleasant side of the "Snotty Porcupine" is that it makes the bearer more sensitive to heavy loads, and it's inconvenient to wear because it constantly emits a mysterious slime. It's a harmless substance, but an extremely unpleasant one. All in all, our team doesn't beleive it won't pose a problem for your soldiers!\n \nBest regards, acad. Sakharov, RAS member</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_giant_small_brother_text"><text>Record 1: "Barely got out of the Dark Valley. We lost Yurka Rowdy - he got teared apart by a Vortex, we didn't even notice a burer pushing him into it with his psi attacks... rest in peace. The group is incomplete without him, we now have less chances to carry this valuable note to the Bar. Burers dragged some poor scientist underground to have a dinner party. He wrote in his PDA that he discovered that it's possible to alter the artifacts into some... modificates, or something... if I got it right. So, he made an artifact of the absolute class, which he called "Giant's Little Brother", by dropping a "Diamond Kolobok" into a "Burner". The scientist guy wrote that this absolute makes the bearer's skin less susceptible to the cuts and bruises, and also deflects a significant percent of bullets caught into the field it generates. As an extra, it also takes the radiation away from the organism, and lowers the food requirements by feeding the bearer with its energy. The information is quite valuable, we need to get it to Sakharov and his team, but we'll need to double our guards just in case, two groups at least." \n \nRecord 2: "We've ran into those Freedom fools! We dropped all five of them. Barely glanced over our trophies - they had excellent guns - as Sanya Cooler had his head smashed with an SVD shot. We hit the spot from where the sniper was shooting with our grenade launchers, but we weren't sure if we killed him. Rinat told me to go while he was covering me. That's a really important information... That asshole sniper doesn't give himself away. An experienced one. Alright, I have to go..."</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_shkura_text"><text>Hi, Vovan. What a dunce you are! Harping on the same tune: "What's going on in the Zone? What's going on in the Zone?". Fucking nothing goes on! It's damn boring here. If we didn't catch those idiots flocking into the Zone for the artifacts, we'd die of boredom. Yeah, it gets terrible sometimes, won't show off for you... When some creature or fuck knows what is howling close to the checkpoint, my hair is rising up in all places, even on the ass... That's considering my rifle is in my hands at all times. Recently we had some fun though, we caught a guy. He walked back out of the Zone, we grabbed him. He was carrying some gem with him, glowing like your riced Lada in the dark! We met him with a third degree ceremony, and he told us that this gem is not just an artifact, but some kind of new stuff. It can mitigate chemical burns or something, and you can ignore the psi. Well, not completely, of course. He also told that it makes the blood coagulate worse. We checked this gem with a dosimeter, and it was clicking! And this guy we caught told us he was carrying this thing to the scientists, for the "public benefit". As he felt more candid, he told us that you can take the "Pellicle" or something, drop it into the "Springboard" and here you go! After an hour you'll get this thing. He told us a lot of other things, he was looking shabby, covered with scars, like a bum. We put him into a cart and send him to the third checkpoint, they will deal with him. Alright, Vovan, take care, I need to fall back into formation. Tell Yulka I love her, remember her, and so on. Good luck!</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_cheshya_text"><text>Gentlemen, I'm glad to tell you that we're found a new transmutation formula! A "Hide" modificate should be exposed to a "Whirlgig" anomaly for 1 hour. The resulting meso-modificate, called "Scales", has the following properties: it mitigates the effect of chemically aggressive environments, and makes one resistant to psi effect. An important warning though! The "Scales" is radioactive and can cause bleeding. We hope that this information will help your noble cause, and are looking forward for our partnership. \n \nBest regards, acad. Sakharov, RAS member</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_pancir_text"><text>Comrade major, we've got a report from the HQ about that "Shell" hyper-modificate we provided them to study. Their analysis shows that the "Shell" (which is a "Scales" meso-modificate altered in a "Fruit Punch" anomaly) reduces bleeding in a person bearing it, neutralised most of the chemically aggressive environments when they come into contact with the skin, and reduces the psi effect a bit. The time required for transmutation is just a hour and a half. The HQ also wanted to have as much study subjects as possible, and the new data on all possible modificates as well, permitting us to do interrogations of the fifth degree. Considering these new orders, I'm asking for your permission to interrogate all stalkers we caught. \n \nCpt. M. Lubyankin</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_simbion_text"><text>Nikolay Valentinovich, I'd like to tell you that the "B" department had an unexpected result in their studies! They discovered that if one places four different artifacts into a "Fruit Punch" anomaly, namely "Jellyfish", "Droplet", "Stone Blood", and the "Thorn", then after four hours and twenty-one minutes of transmutation, a new artifact with wonderful new properties will form. This modificate, temporarily named "Simbion", blocks 30% of psi emission, and increases the bearer's health! We carried our experiments on prisoners, subjected to the attacks of our captive Archibald. Taking into account that this controllers is contained in captivity for a long time already, and he got a bit weaker without replenishing his energy with blowout residues, I still consider that these psi blocking abilities are exceptional! I've prepared the report for the headquarters, awaiting for your comments and the permission to send the data. \n \nprof. Snegiryov, the head of the "B" department</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_dummy_text"><text>Report #14/7 for the "Deceiver" project\nTo prof. Nikolay Dmitrievich Sazonov, the head of the K-32 research department\n \nDear Nikolay Dmitrievich, we completed our studies of the "Moon Empty" hyper-modificate. During our experiments, 7 (seven) subjects were destroyed, 5 (five) degraded, 1 (one) showed a positive result in a transmutation chain. \n \nWhen placing the "Moon Empty" hyper-modificate into a "Fruit Punch" anomaly, there was no rejection as it was in "Burner" and "Vortex" cases. After 1 hour, 23 minutes and 56 seconds the artifact got the properties of the absolute class, namely: increasing the fire resistance, increasing the stamina a bit, significantly increasing the electrick shock and radiation resistances. The artifact was temporarily named "Pudding".\n \nFurther exposure to the "Fruit Punch" anomaly didn't yield any results, as the artifact was rejected by the anomaly. \n \nI consider the result exceptional, and think that the "Deciever" project is completed successfully. I've sent the full observation records to the server.\n \nResearch group 7 head, V.A. Avakyan</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_fake_text"><text>To get the "Sunlight" modificate, one has to place the "Moonlight" artifact into the "Burner" anomaly. After approximately four hours, a modificate with following properties will form: great stamina increase, high temperature susceptibility decrease, slight decrease of electric shock sensitivity. The side effect is the radioactivity of the artifact. The information requires additional verification.</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_gigant_text"><text>I see everything, I feel everything, I understand everything... I can't change anything. I know it will hurt...\n \nController doesn't kill instantly. And doesn't extinguish your consciousness right away, you'll even have your will and your desires for a while... Enough to regret that. But a human is a weird creature: he wants to live even when he understands that it would be better to die. \nI will whisper. While he doesn't see me, while I still can move my lips at my own will. \n \nA weird artifact is glowing ther, in the dark, next to the anomaly that has eaten both of my companions... despite that several days have passed already, and a couple of previous blowouts changed the anomalous landscape beyond recognition. This is the third. \n \nHe doesn't like blowouts. There's a hole with no anomalies. He hides there, when the sky becomes crimson, plug the entrance with a pseudogiant under his control... Giant is roaring, scratches the walls with his hands, trying to get inside, to get away from the scorching fire approaching from the north. Little does he know! The entrance is too tight for a pseudogiant to fit. He's screeching and squirming, switching to an insufferable ultrasound... in the corners of his eyes, huge like plates, aquamarine tears are swelling and dropping down. The giant is hurt. He's crying. Look at that... and I can't cry. \n \nThe controller extinguished Motya immediately. Just looked in his direction, and he walked into a nearby anomaly like an indifferent mannequine. Just like he was, with his loot, his backpack, his gun... The gun surely didn't help him much! And it didn't help us, the torpid ones. We just stayed and looked at this creature taking the human remains out of the sparkling "Electra", spreading it out on the rusty dried grass... and licked its lips, and even smirked, I think! \n \nMotya even had an artifact protecting him from telepathy. He showed us his precious "Chimera's Tears" many times... The backpack remained intact and didn't interest the controller. He didn't even notice when a white flash erased the world for a moment. We notices that, and noticed that a new glow appeared next to a shimmering anomaly - one of Motya's artifacts transmuted there. But we didn't care anymore. \n \nOwl happened to be second. Just after the second blowout. On his own, without any screaming as well. Here was Owl and the "Springboard", and the moment later there was a bunch of bloody remains, and indifferent, emotionless eyes of the controller. He was hungry and got himself some food... Now it's my turn. \n \nI know that the controller is hungry again. And there's a "Springboard" just spawned nearby. But first I need to go and get something that's glowing next to a non-disappearing anomaly... He told me to go. I'll go. I'll finish my whispering and go. Because he told me. And the artifact is green. Green like those tears. Tears of the pseudogiant during a blowout. Here, I see it like it's there. No, it's not green. It's aquamarine... a weird word... where did it come from? I don't remember. I need to grab it. He tells me to grab it. \n \nI'm coming...</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_burer_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>...Sergey Romanovich, I want to pay your attention to Appendix 12 to the latest monthly report of the Kratov group, namely to the results of "Specimen 112-12-3" study. Preliminary results hint that making absolutes with these properties en masse should be made our top priority to protect our expeditions and receiving grants for the "Apostle" project. We determined that it's possbile to make these artifacts artificially, despite prof. Saraev estimates, who was asserting the impossibility of such process. You'll see the evidence yourself by reading the full report. In short, placing a hyper-modificate temporarily named "Burer Grandmother's Beads" (sorry for the stalker slang, we already got used to it here) into an anomaly with a third type singularity ("Burner") for an hour, into the region of subcritical intensity of torsion and alpha fields, produces a new artifact temporarily named "Burer's Great-Grandmother's Beads". It only possesses positive properties and can be rightfully named an absolute of this artifact modification chain. There's also an unusual and tragic story related to how we received a sample for our experiments. But things like that are better discussed with alcohol, and my holiday will be coming soon, so I hope to tell it to you in person, at a night camprife. Stalkers are reckless people, and in their crazy experiments with "Burners" (that's the name they gave to the process of supermatter transmutation in singularity creases, can you imagine that!) they are similar to Monolithians. \n \nBe also sure to send my regards to your wife, Irina Semyonovna, a nice woman who helped us with the last month's supply. Without her patronage, we would'd have seen our new mass spectrometers for another year...</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dikoobraz_text"><text>\n \nModificate "Porcupine", which is effective against radiation, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Sea Urchin"%c[default] artifact, fully positive,\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner"%c[default]anomaly.\nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]about one hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_electra_dikoobraz_text"><text>\n \nMeso-modificate "Electric Porcupine" which is effective against radiation and electric shock, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Porcupine"%c[default] modificate\nby transmuting it in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_sopl_dikoobraz_text"><text>\n \nHyper-modificate "Snotty Porcupine" which is effective against radiation, chemical burns and bleeding, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Electric Porcupine"%c[default] meso-modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Friut Punch"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]one hour and a half%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_stone_dikoobraz_text"><text>\n \nAbsolute "Stone Porcupine" which is effective against radiation, bleeding, and shock waves, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Snotty Porcupine"%c[default] meso-modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Springboard"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]one hour and a half%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_steel_kolobok_text"><text>\n \nModificate "Steel Kolobok" which is effective against cuts and bruises, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Kolobok"%c[default] artifact\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Springboard"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_titan_kolobok_text"><text>\n \nMeso-modificate "Titanium Kolobok" which is effective against cuts and bruises, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Steel Kolobok"%c[default] modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Whirlgig"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]about an hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_almaz_kolobok_text"><text>\n \nHyper-modificate "Diamond Kolobok" which is effective against cuts and bruises, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Kolobok"%c[default] artifact\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]one hour and a half%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_souls_bengal_text"><text>\n \nAbsolute "Crystal Bengal Soul" which is effective against radiation and improves health, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Crystal Soul"%c[default] hyper-modificate\nby transmuting it in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour and 30 minutes%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_souls_drops_text"><text>\n \nModificate "Soul Droplet" which is effective against radiation and improves health, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Soul"%c[default] artifact, fully positive,\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>
    
<string id="enc_amk_recipt_souls_fire_text"><text>\n \nMeso-modificate "Fiery Soul" which is effective against heat and improves health, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Soul Droplet"%c[default] modificate\nby transmuting it in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_souls_cristal_text"><text>\n \nHyper-modificate "Crystal Soul" which is effective against radiation and improves health, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Fiery Soul"%c[default] meso-modificate,\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour and 30 minutes%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>
    
<string id="enc_amk_recipt_tears_electra_text"><text>\n \nModificate "Electra's Tears" which improves stamina is produced from the \n%c[green]"Moonlight"%c[default] artifact, fully positive,\nby transmuting it in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_tears_fire_text"><text>\n \nMeso-modificate "Fire Tears" which improves stamina is produced from the \n%c[green]"Electra's Tears"%c[default] modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_tears_chimaera_text"><text>\n \nHyper-modificate "Chimera's Tears" which improves stamina is produced from the \n%c[green]"Fire Tears"%c[default] meso-modificate,\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour and 30 minutes%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_tears_gigant_text"><text>\n \nAbsolute "Giant's Tear" which improves stamina is produced from the \n%c[green]"Chimera's Tears"%c[default] hyper-modificate\nby transmuting it in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]an hour and a half%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>\n \nModificate "Grandmother's Beads" which is effective against bullets and improves carried weight, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Mama's Beads"%c[default] artifact\nby transmuting it in an %c[UI_orange]"Electra"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>\n \nMeso-modificate "Great Grandmother's Beads" which is effective against bullets and improves carried weight, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Grandmother's Beads"%c[default] modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_burer_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>\n \nHyper-modificate "Burer's Grandmother's Beads" which is effective against bullets and improves carried weight, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Great Grandmother's Beads"%c[default] meso-modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Whirlgig"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour and 30 minutes%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_burer_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text"><text>\n \nAbsolute "Great Burer's Grandmother's Beads" which is effective against bullets and improves carried weight, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Great Grandmother's Beads"%c[default] hyper-modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour and 30 minutes%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_giant_small_brother_text"><text>\n \nAbsolute "Giant's Younger Brother" which is effective against cuts, bruises, and radiation, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Diamond Kolobok"%c[default] hyper-modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]one hour and a half%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_shkura_text"><text>\n \nModificate "Hide" which restores psy-health and is effective against telepathy and chemical burns, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Pellicle"%c[default] artifact\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Springboard"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_cheshya_text"><text>\n \nMeso-modificate "Scales" which restores psy-health and is effective against telepathy and chemical burns, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Hide"%c[default] artifact\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Whirlgig"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_pancir_text"><text>\n \nHyper-modificate "Armor" which restores psy-health and is effective against telepathy, bleeding, and chemical burns, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Scales"%c[default] artifact\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_simbion_text"><text>\n \nUnique modificate "Simbion" which is effective against telepathy and improves health, is produced from 4 artifacts:\n \n• %c[red]fully negative%c[default] "Jellyfish"\n• %c[red]fully negative%c[default] "Thorn"\n• %c[green]fully positive%c[default] "Stone Blood"\n• %c[green]fully positive%c[default] "Droplet"\nby transmuting it in the %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]5-10min%c[default] of Zone time. In some cases, the transmutation can take up to %c[green]4 hours%c[default].</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_puding_text"><text>\n \nAbsolute "Pudding" which is effective against burns, electric shock, and radiation, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Moon Empty"%c[default] hyper-modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]one hour and a half%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_fire_text"><text>\n \nModificate "Fire Empty" which is effective against burns and improves stamina, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Empty"%c[default] artifact\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_bright_text"><text>\n \nMeso-modificate "Bright Empty" which is effective against burns and improves stamina, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Fire Empty"%c[default] modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Fruit Punch"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_moon_text"><text>\n \nHyper-modificate "Moon Empty" which improves stamina and is effective against burns and electric shock, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Bright Empty"%c[default] meso-modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]an hour and a half%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_controller_skalp_text"><text>\n \nAbsolute "Controller's Scalp" which is effective against telepathy, chemical burns, and bleeding, is produced from the \n%c[green]"Shell"%c[default] hyper-modificate\nby transmuting it in a %c[UI_orange]"Burner"%c[default] anomaly.\n \nTransmutation is completed in %c[green]1 hour and 30 minutes%c[default] of Zone time.</text></string>
	
<string id="blowout_not_sleep"><text>A blowout! Can't fall asleep!</text></string>
<string id="cant_sleep_equip"><text>Can't fit inside with my gear on!</text></string>
<string id="not_need_sleep"><text>I don't want to sleep...</text></string>
<string id="not_need_sleep_nrg"><text>Can't fall asleep! The energy drink is in effect... Damn!</text></string>
<string id="not_need_sleep_enemy"><text>Not a best time to be sleeping with enemies nearby!</text></string>
<string id="not_need_sleep_undegrourd"><text>Underground is not the best place to sleep.</text></string>
<string id="trans_finished_title"><text>Artifact transmutation result: </text></string>
<string id="trans_finished_msg"><text>Artifact transmutation result: </text></string>
	
<string id="stalker_died"><text>Stalker died:</text></string>
	
<string id="alc_too_much_die"><text>Phew... One can die from drinking that much!</text></string>
<string id="alc_too_much"><text>I've drank a bit too much...</text></string>
<string id="alc_todo_alcoholic"><text>Damn, I seem to became alcoholic.</text></string>
<string id="alc_need_drink"><text>Damn... I need to drink...</text></string>
<string id="alc_need_drink_big"><text>Damn... I feel sick! I need to drink!</text></string>
<string id="alc_coded"><text>Finally, I've treated my alcoholism...</text></string>
<string id="alc_no_more_need"><text>I got out of drinking... I need to stay clean for a week or two now...</text></string>
	
<string id="amk_warn_trans"><text>WARNING!!! Buffer overflow! Transmutation data isn't saved! Wait for the transmutations to finish and try again.</text></string>
<string id="amk_warn_trans_critical"><text>WARNING!!! Buffer overflow! Current transmutations won't be finished. It's recommended to restore a previous savegame.</text></string>
<string id="amk_warn_attention"><text>Warning! The amount of data being saved is about to hit the limit! Complete all uncompleted jobs. Wait for all transmutations to finish. Don't take new jobs. Don't start new transmutations.</text></string>
	
<string id="amk_sleep_title"><text>Sleep</text></string>
<string id="amk_sleep_one_hour"><text>Take a nap</text></string>
<string id="amk_sleep_three_hours"><text>Sleep</text></string>
<string id="amk_sleep_five_hours"><text>Have a good sleep</text></string>
<string id="amk_sleep_until_full_health"><text>Sleep until healed</text></string>

<string id="amk_dots_title"><text>Caption</text></string>
<string id="amk_dots_done"><text>Mark</text></string>
	
<string id="amk_welcome_title"><text>Greetings from the AMK Team!</text></string>
<string id="amk_welcome_msg"><text>%c[255,255,128,128]Have a good time playing the game!\n%c[default]AMK MOD 1.4.1</text></string>
	
<string id="rep_no_weapon_in_slot"><text>No weapon in the slot</text></string>
	
<string id="rep_not_need"><text>Weapon doesn't need to be repaired</text></string>
	
<string id="rep_need_big"><text>Weapon needs substantial repair</text></string>

<string id="story1_text_0"><text>You're looking depressed, what's up?</text></string>
<string id="story1_text_1"><text>Listen, I'll tell you a story. One stalker told me what happened to him. \nHe found a cigar case once and brought it to Sidor. He looked at it and told him it's just a useless junk. But there was scratched something on the back side. Sidor took a looking glass and read the names: Timokha, Moose and some others, I forgot. He told he got a debt recorded on Timokha in his book, and he doesn't know others.</text></string>
<string id="story1_text_2"><text>So what... what kind of story is that?</text></string>
<string id="story1_text_22"><text>I know this story, not interested.</text></string>
<string id="story1_text_3"><text>Wait, I haven't told you everything yet. That stalker got his cigar case back, you know - the cigars are crumpled easily, it's better to keep them in a rigid box. He asked at the campfire by the way, who are these Timokha and others. Somebody, I think Gray, told him he saw this cigar box in the hands of Sashka Lucky. He was staying around here, at the Garbage, and then said he's fed up with this pile of shit and he's going to get more loot... and left to some other place... Yeah, about Timokha... He came to Gray someday, questioning him about Sashka Lucky, where he was, what's he up to. There were two more goons with him, who looked more of the bandit types than diggers, but they kept their mouths shut and were looking out for something. Gray told him that Lucky probably left for the Bar. And those three left and never got back. \nSo... that stalker who found a cigar box had some business in the Bar once. He met a man who had a friend who found a field filled with artifacts. What a luck! He grabbed everything he could, of course, but he couldn't take everything with him. He went to Barkeep to sell his loot, you know how it's done - stalkers are trying to make it look they have nothing interesting, and quietly pass him the valuable loot while nobody's looking. So either he got a hole in his backpack or he gave himself out somehow, but somebody seen that he has much more than he'd like to talk about.</text></string>
<string id="story1_text_4"><text>What happened then?</text></string>
<string id="story1_text_5"><text>Take your guess. This is not an aristocratic society... So later he found his friend, almost dead... He only managed to tell that he got caught by some scumbags, they took his belongings and threw him into a hole until he tells them where he found such artifacts. He was silent like a rock, they beat him. While he was in the hole, he scratched the names he heard on the cigar box... And then he dies. \nThe most interesting thing is than man from the Bar was the same who gave him the box. But they took the box and the rest of his stuff anyway.</text></string>
<string id="story1_text_6"><text>Sad ending.</text></string>
<string id="story1_text_7"><text>That's not the ending yet. That man met by the stalker, told him that he was trying to track these bastards for two months, and did it... one by one. He got even with them for Sashka Lucky... But they didn't have the box with them, maybe they sold it for drinks. It was valuable for him as a memory, because nothing else is left after his friend, you know.\nAnd that stalker says, here's your box, I found it by accident! Take it and remember your friend. So the ending isn't so sad, as you see.</text></string>
<string id="story1_text_8"><text>Yeah... you could say so.</text></string>

<string id="story2_text_0"><text>What are you thinking about? It's like you remembered something...</text></string>
<string id="story2_text_1"><text>I'll tell you a story I've heard recently. A stalker found some thingy, you know, a figurine cut out of wood and polished... there's even a scientific name for it, can't recall... Alright, not the point. People find a lot of different stuff in the Zone, from garbage to useful things, but he haven't seen anything like that before. It was a... controller maybe, or a bloodsucker... cut skillfully, and the wood was weird, black and polished.</text></string>
<string id="story2_text_2"><text>So what... something was waiting for the blowout to end and cut it with a knife.</text></string>
<string id="story2_text_22"><text>You told me this one, second time isn't that interesting.</text></string>
<string id="story2_text_3"><text>Nah, you don't cut something like this out of boredom. Somebody did their best, that was a masterful work. At the bottom there was a double zero, or a double O - like a brand, get it? The stalker wanted to sell it to a trader, there's a lot of collectors out there, let the trader deal with them. He went to the Bar... and he found the figurine in the Dark Valley. At the Garbage, he sat by a campfire to have some rest. And showed it to another stalker, who told him: "I saw that brand. It's not a brand actually, just a Pashka Four-Eyed signature. He signs his belongings with it, his canteen, his pistol, he even sew a label to his backpack. He's weird. He wanted to prove his worth to everyone, gain some weight in stalkers' eyes, but he's actually a wimp..." He directed him to the Bar.</text></string>
<string id="story2_text_4"><text>Yeah, and you're trying to tell me he met Four-Eyed in the Bar?</text></string>
<string id="story2_text_5"><text>Yeah, don't laugh... If he wouldn't have met him, the Four-Eyed wouldn't be laughing either. He thought about, you know... They still had a full-fledged arena there, there were serious fights in there, until Dutyers shut that ancient Rome entertainment down. Four-Eyed wanted to gain some reputation on the arene, to became famous in the Zone... What a fool, he didn't even know how to cock the AK.\nWell, what I'm on about... So he sees a guy with glasses boozing in the Bar, and asks him: "Are you Pashka Four-Eyed?" "Yeah...", "What are you doing here?" And he told stalker about his arena plan. He was hesitating to do it, that's why the stalker found him still alive - a coward might survive longer than a brave one in the Zone.</text></string>
<string id="story2_text_6"><text>So what's the point, I don't get it..</text></string>
<string id="story2_text_7"><text>The point is that the figurine really belonged to Four-Eyed. That was his talisman, you see. It was a gift from his boxer friend, who didn't lose a single fight. He gave him this figurine which has been cut out of the special rosewood. Told him that he rubs it before a fight and he is sure to score a win. He was making fun of him, I think. And this Four-Eyed beleived him and lost his "talisman" somewhere. Got frighened by a dog pack, ran away, and the figurine slipped out of his backpack. Because he "forgot to rub it"... If he still had his talisman with himself, he'd been much more self-confident and walked into the arena.\nIsn't he a fool? Tell me. Stalker gave him the talisman back, but said: "You can rub it against your ass as much as you want, but promise me not to check if it's working by fighting in the arena! Get lost, and don't let me see you around the arena!" Well, he knocked some sense into his head. I even met Four-Eyed the other day at the Garbage. He just helped him.</text></string>
<string id="story2_text_8"><text>Yeah, he got lucky. There are some weird people around...</text></string>

<string id="story3_text_0"><text>What are you laughing at? Care to tell?</text></string>
<string id="story3_text_1"><text>Heard about the cultist priest?.. So some priest came into the Zone once. Not Diodor, everybody knows him already, another one... and he wasn't a priest, just some weird guy or a cultist. Something dawned upon him, he met HIM... fuck me if I know who, but he came to believe in Him, looked like he's got a few screws loose.</text></string>
<string id="story3_text_2"><text>How do you know about this? Did he tell you?</text></string>
<string id="story3_text_22"><text>Ah... I've heard this one, you can stop.</text></string>
<string id="story3_text_3"><text>I haven't met him, this story has been told to be by another stalker... But you wanted to hear something interesting, so listen and don't interrupt me. When he came to himself after his "vision", he saw an icon in his hands. I mean, how is it called... panagia... yeah, that's the word. It's a small decorated icon. But he had a simple one, just a picture carved out of wood: a controller in the center and twelve zombies around him - six to the left and six to the right. I know it because I've met an artist who coincidentally told me this story, and told me it was him who carved this icon. He's drawing all sorts of stuff, I even saw his drawings in somebody's collection, he's an avant-garde artist, native to the Zone... I haven't heard of him for a while, he just disappeared, and I wanted to buy something from him...</text></string>
<string id="story3_text_4"><text>Don't get distracted, you were telling about the priest.</text></string>
<string id="story3_text_5"><text>Yeah, so we spoke more with that artist, and he said about the priest. He met him in an empty trailer somewhere, almost starved to death. The artist offered some food to him, but he refused: "I'm fasting and meditating", he said. "You don't know the peace, don't know that everything is vanity of vanities, and that there's only Him" "Who is him?" - asked an artist. "The Supreme Controller with his 12 apostles appeared before me, and left me a panagia, and told me to remember Him and pray to His glory. But I sinned against His will, because I failed to preserve His gift. Now I will keep the fast until He comes and forgives me".</text></string>
<string id="story3_text_6"><text>Yeah... he probably fell under a controller's gaze, or smoked hell of a lot of weed...</text></string>
<string id="story3_text_7"><text>Likely the latter, because there was a specific smell there, as he said. The artist sees that the priest will die soon, and refuses the food. And tells him: "Is your faith really worth dying? Come on, I saw the controller, he's there... sunbathing in the lowland, he already said he forgave you..." The priest doesn't believe him: "Don't be foolish. It's no use arguing with you. You're probably new to the Zone and haven't understood anything yet. Once you live there long enough, you'll have questions for which you won't get any answers". Alright, and the artist is like: "Do you think a controller will answer these? I've seen plenty of evangelists here. If you want to spread your faith, why are you sitting there? Go outside and spread it, you will just die here". And the priest is like: "Your questions aren't mature yet. We'll talk later if you survive... I'm fasting and praying here, because I've lost His gift". \n"Well, things are in bad here", thought the artist. And told him: "What if HE will send me to find your panagia and I'll find it, will you heed His words?" "Yes..." He had to draw the controller and 12 zombies in a hurry. Found some piece of wood, he has the paint with himself, he's making sketches on the go all the time. Found a bottle, broke it, stuffed some glass pieces at the sides... I mean, it was a work to be proud of, he's got hands of gold, I've seen his drawings... He got back and said: "Here... HE gave me this panagia, and a couple of canned meat cans as well. Said you must not die fasting, and permitted you to carry His word among the people". I don't know what happened to the artist, but the cultist has been seen at the Rostok once.</text></string>
<string id="story3_text_8"><text>What can I say... doesn't matter who and for what purpose walks into the Zone, but nobody survives alone here.</text></string>

<string id="story4_text_0"><text>So how's the Zone to you?</text></string>
<string id="story4_text_1"><text>Different each time. Sometimes it can hit you between your eyes, sometimes it gives you gifts. I know of a case... are you listening?</text></string>
<string id="story4_text_2"><text>Yeah, tell me.</text></string>
<string id="story4_text_22"><text>Nah, people tell all sorts of things here... You'd better drink.</text></string>
<string id="story4_text_3"><text>Hm... So that scientist told me and Kostya Machinegun to transmute a certain artifact. \nWe bought what we needed in the bar, came to the Warehouses, everything was fine. Found a "Vortex", Kostya dragged the components into it with a rope, we lighted a campfire an a nearby house, waiting for it to finish.\nAfter about an hour we got out to check if it's ready. I see our beauty jumping up and down by the "Vortex". I covered it with a container, stick a board below it to avoid touching it, and turned it upside down. We decided to drink to it, right in that house. \nVodka is pouring into glasses, great...\nIt's got dark already.\nI'm raising my head and see two huge eyes looking at me. Mother of dog, a chimera! My teammate saw it too, raised his rifle and fired a bust into it.\nBut he missed, it seems.\nHe jumped up to his feet and ran to the exit, yelling something. I saw how the chimera just teared him apart like a toy. His body fell to one side, legs to another one. \nAnd I just froze, the terror has paralyzed me. I saw him opening his mouth and croaking...</text></string>
<string id="story4_text_4"><text>A terryfing story, what did you do?</text></string>
<string id="story4_text_5"><text>Chimera sat down and rubbed its snout against a concrete slab. I moved backwards, but stubmled over somthing and fell. Looked below, but there was nothing, turned my flashlight on but only saw an empty floor. But there was something. And here I saw some sparks, just like something is striking a match by my feet. An artifact? But an invisible one? It cannot be! There's death nearby, my friend got teared apart, and the only thing I can think of is if I stumbled upon an artifact. I reached my hand to the sparkling spot, but the chimera started scraping the house wall. I felt this sound with every cell of my skin. It was like scales fell from my eyes, I jumped to my feet and took a leap into the opposite window, head first. I ran away like crazy, holding my container tight. Now I think it might be worth it to return and search for that invisible thing. But I can't. I just can't...</text></string>
<string id="story4_text_6"><text>Where? Where did it happen? I may go and check it.</text></string>
<string id="story4_text_7"><text>Would you, now?\n...\nI'll check it myself after recovering. Must be worth something. So... Keep that in mind...</text></string>
<string id="story4_text_8"><text>Well, suit yourself.</text></string>

<string id="story5_text_0"><text>Why are you so gloomy? Tell me a story...</text></string>
<string id="story5_text_1"><text>Gloomy? Nah, I'm always like this. A story, you say, I've got plenty. Ummm... Have you heard about the artifact sets?</text></string>
<string id="story5_text_2"><text>No, tell it to me.</text></string>
<string id="story5_text_22"><text>I've heard it, relax.</text></string>
<string id="story5_text_3"><text>I had a case which is still bizarre to me, despite that I'm in the Zone for a long time already and got used to everything. A scientist has offered my a job to carry some artifacts. All artifacts were the emerald ones, "Wrenched", "Stone Blood" and "Jellyfish". Beautiful ones, good protection from the cuts and bruises, a bit heavy though. I've been promised some good loot for this. I've been heading that way anyway, so I agreed. Decided to take a shortcut through the Agroprom. Everything was fine, but just as I've walked over a hill near the military base, I've encountered a pack of dogs and a pseudogiant. I climbed a pile of concrete slabs, they knocked out the gun out of my hands. I took my pistol and killed four of them, but ran out of ammo. I decided to activate the artifacts I've been carrying, just for a dash to my shotgun. I've attached all three emerald artifacts to my belt, turned it on... Something flashed quickly, then there was just darkness and a lot of dust.</text></string>
<string id="story5_text_4"><text>Huh? How could that be? What was that?</text></string>
<string id="story5_text_5"><text>Listen, don't interrupt me. \n I've turned my flashlight on and was stupefied: it turned to be the Agroprom Underground. How? What happened? I've just slowly crawled to the exit, found a soldier body, took his AK with a dozen rounds in the magazine... Climbed out to the surface, went to the guys in the main building, and discovered that my artifacts just disappeared from the belt! Drank a bottle, grieved over it, slept if off, and climbed back to look for the artifacts. Ran into a bloodsucker, killed it miraculously, but still didn't find the artifacts. Went to the Barkeep. Told him, he didn't beleive me, and was swearing at me. He said I probably sold it for drinks, or had them pinched away while I was sleeping. So I've got my hopes for the reward flopped, and Barkeep is still angry about it. Later I've heard that all three green artifacts make some kind of a set, and it affects space shifting somehow. But you wouldn't gather such a set to try it out for witnesses. It could cast you into a place you won't be able to get out...</text></string>
<string id="story5_text_6"><text>I don't beleive it. Seems like a fairy tale.</text></string>
<string id="story5_text_7"><text>Fairy tale? See for yourself... You'll beleive me when you get burned by this.</text></string>
<string id="story5_text_8"><text>We'll see...</text></string>

<string id="story6_text_0"><text>Why are you so gloomy? Tell me a story...</text></string>
<string id="story6_text_1"><text>Gloomy? Nah, I'm always like this. A story, you say, I've got plenty. Ummm... Have you heard about the artifact sets?</text></string>
<string id="story6_text_2"><text>No, tell it to me.</text></string>
<string id="story6_text_22"><text>I've heard it, relax.</text></string>
<string id="story6_text_3"><text>We were going through the Wild Territory with Gena Foreman once, as we ran into bandits. We walked all the way from the Yantar, from Sakharov, and sold him a lot of stuff. We didn't want to give up that easily, gave them a real fight. Gena had some grenades with him, and that saved us. Beat them off and were going to move further, but one of the gopniks was still alive, waited for us to turn our backs to him, and discharged his gun into Gena's back. He had a tough suit, but it was no use against a point black shot from a shotgun. He stood no chance. I didn't mess it up and sent an entire magazine through the scumbag. I've approached Gena, but he was barely breathing already. I thought he was done for as I recalled that we didn't sell the "Soul", "Stone Blood", and "Meat Chunk" to Sakharov. Opened up the container, attached them to Genka's belt, and turned it on. Should have been enough to make it to the Bar. The artifacts started taking effect, I saw him blushing, and calmed down. Little did I know! Suddenly, the blowout struck. What a bad luck. I've carried Genka on my shoulders, dragging the backpack behind...</text></string>
<string id="story6_text_4"><text>So? What happened?</text></string>
<string id="story6_text_5"><text>Listen, don't interrupt me.\n It was heavy, the ammo, guns, a couple containers for each of us. You wouldn't just drop that. I'm realizing that the blowout is peaking soon and we won't make it, I feel sick and dizzy, but I'm dragging Gena with me - if we'll die, we'll die together, brother! Crawling into the hangar and rolling into it head first, losing my consciousness...\n...\nI don't know how long I've been here, but when I opened my eyes, Gena sat next to me and warmed the canned meat on the fire. Smiled to me, told me to wake up. I coulnd't tell a word, how is it possible, he was dying on me, and here he is, warming the food up. We talked a lot after that. These artifacts I've put onto Genka's belt, expired and lost all their properties in the blowout, which was particularly strong this time.\nBut, as Genka said, something happened with them the moment blowout peaked, and he started to come back to life rapidly. The bleeding has stopped, the pain went away...\nSo he came back to life...\nThe problem is that those artifacts are of no use anymore, there's nothing to sell. But I think, maybe it's one of the sets experienced stalkers are talking about.</text></string>
<string id="story6_text_6"><text>Were those artifacts special or something?</text></string>
<string id="story6_text_7"><text>Who knows. We didn't pay attention to that at first, and then we couldn't determine that.</text></string>
<string id="story6_text_8"><text>Yeah, just the Zone being the Zone...</text></string>

<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_0"><text>I want to buy some recipes.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_11"><text>Alright but I'm busy right now. Come back a couple hours later if you'd still want them...</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_1"><text>Alright. I know about some ways of producing unique artifacts. I guess you understand that it will cost you something. What exactly do you need? I have recipes for ordinary artifacts and for unique ones. Ordinary ones are cheaper, uniques will cost you more.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_21"><text>Let's see your ordinary recipes.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_22"><text>I want to see your uniques.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_23"><text>Hm... I'm hard up for money right now.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_33"><text>Alright, come back when you need something.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_31"><text>Ordinary ones... Wait a moment, I'll see if I have something... Alright. This one is not confirmed yet. This one crippled those who are trying it, \nand those are already confirmed by stalkers to produce something useful:</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_41"><text>I guess I'll take the first one.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_42"><text>The second one seems interesting.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_43"><text>I didn't know about the third one. I'll take it.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_44"><text>I'll make use of the fourth one...</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_45"><text>Wow! The fifth one! I'll take it!</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_46"><text>That's for the Empty? I'll take it, no questions asked.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_47"><text>Nothing interesting, I'll come back later...</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_51"><text>Take notes:</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_52"><text>Right, see for yourself:</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_53"><text>Here, take it.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_54"><text>You'll need it, for sure...</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_55"><text>Tooth never lies, take notes:</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_56"><text>Yeah, the Empty. Take notes...</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_6"><text>Done. I'll try it some time.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_32"><text>Want something unique? Of course! They are good, but they also cost a lot of money! A have a recipe you can trust:</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_421"><text>Yeah, I don't have it, I'll take it.</text></string>
<string id="amk_recipt_osvedomitel_521"><text>Right choice, write it down:</text></string>
</string_table>
