<?xml version="1.0" ecoding="windows-1251" ?>
<!--new_docent_detector-->	
<string id="bar_docent_detector_0"><text>Barkeep said you've been looking for me?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_1"><text>Marked One! Speak of the devil... Good ol' Sakharov gave me another job. Mutants which used to only inhabit Radar have been sighted recently in some places that were relatively quiet before. They want to make a device or something to track mutant migration patterns. Should be a really promising job.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_2"><text>So let them make it. How on earth did you get involved in this?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_3"><text>I promised Sakharov that I would contact the Hunters through my own channels. They will assist in tracking the uncommon mutants down. But... they refuse to kill them themselves. It's a matter of principle they say.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_3"><text>Principles... hadn't noticed they had any. So what do you want from me?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_4"><text>For the tracking to be more precise, the device needs to be tuned to the DNA of a specific mutant. If only they had their body parts in sufficient quantities, the job would have progressed much faster.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_5"><text>So what mutants are they trying to track?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_6"><text>The most dangerous ones, I think: bloodsuckers, chimeras, controllers, pseudogiants.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_7"><text>That's one hell of a job. The dangerous ones. So much for their principles.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_8"><text>I've contacted the Hunters. They promised to tell me when they track the specific creatures down. So, do you agree to help Sakharov out?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_9"><text>I may agree to help. I'd like to know what I get out of this though. As far as I understand, you didn't take the burden of science upon yourself for mere gratitude.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_10"><text>Sakharov got me some ammo and medicines. So I'll compensate your expenses in excess. And after you complete the job, you'll have exclusive access to the knowledge of the uncommon creatures' whereabouts. You won't have to run around the entire Zone if you need a specific mutant part. So, do you agree?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_101"><text>Nah, Docent, I'll manage without this job.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_102"><text>Deal. I'll be waiting for any further news.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_11"><text>Suit yourself, I'll find someone else to take the job.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_12"><text>Trust me, you won't regret it.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_detector_13"><text>Take care... researcher.</text></string>

<string id="tex_bar_docent_detector1"><text>\nDocent needs three jaws from the bloodsuckers inhabiting Dark Valley.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_0"><text>I've seen the message, have you been looking for me?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_1"><text>Our conversation about the device, do you remember it? I have some info about a bloodsucker lair. You still interested?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_21"><text>So where have they seen them? I hope I won't need to run across the entire Zone for them.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_22"><text>I don't have time right now, I'll come back later.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_3"><text>No, it's not far, just over in the Dark Valley. The Hunters told me they've seen a pack of these suckers. They were of some special variety, they said.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_4"><text>So... that's all?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_5"><text>You'll have to try to cut out three jaws to bring back.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_61"><text>Deal, I'll bring you the jaws.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_62"><text>Three?! I don't like this idea.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_71"><text>I've got their lair marked in your PDA. Here, have some ammo.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_72"><text>Suit yourself, I'll find someone else to take the job.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_start_8"><text>Take care... researcher.</text></string>

<string id="bar_docent_1detector_done_0"><text>I brought you the mutant parts for the device.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_done_1"><text>Device? What device?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_done_2"><text>Don't be a laggard, Docent. I've brought three jaws, just like we agreed.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_done_3"><text>Ah, jaws, now I remember.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_done_4"><text>Take them, they are starting to smell already. Those turned out to be some fierce suckers.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_done_5"><text>Yeah, I asked the Hunters to choose the most seasoned ones. They have the purest DNA, or so I've been told.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_done_6"><text>I did my part of the job. What about the reward?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_done_7"><text>Sure, take this. And here's a bonus to drink to a successful deal.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_1detector_done_8"><text>Speak to me again if you need something else.</text></string>

<string id="tex_bar_docent_detector2"><text>\nDocent needs three claws from chimeras inhabiting the Tunnel.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_0"><text>I've seen the message, have you been looking for me?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_1"><text>Our conversation about the device, do you remember it? I have some info about a chimera lair. Are you ready to continue our research?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_21"><text>Where have they seen them?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_22"><text>I don't have time right now, I'll come back later.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_3"><text>Here, it's not far. You've been to the Tunnel before, right? The Hunters told me that they've seen several specimens here.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_4"><text>So... what is expected from me this time?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_5"><text>Five claws are needed to tune the device, I think it should be enough.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_6"><text>What?! You'll get exhausted just from cutting a single one. Do you know how much ammo is going to be wasted?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_7"><text>Well, so get me three then, at least.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_8"><text>I won't risk my ass for nothing.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_9"><text>I'll try to compensate you with some ammo and medicine, and I'll tip a little extra.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_91"><text>Deal. Go ahead and mark them in my PDA.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_92"><text>I don't like this idea.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_11"><text>I've got their lair marked in your PDA. Here's a little something...</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_12"><text>Suit yourself, I'll find someone else to take the job.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_start_13"><text>Take care... researcher.</text></string>

<string id="bar_docent_2detector_done_0"><text>I've brought the claws for the device.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_done_1"><text>Claws... what claws?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_done_2"><text>Docent, did you hit your head?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_done_3"><text>Sorry, now I remember.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_done_4"><text>Take these claws. Those turned out to be some fierce chimeras.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_done_5"><text>Yeah, I asked the hunters to choose the most seasoned ones. They have the purest DNA, or so I've been told.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_done_6"><text>Do you remember our deal? I'm waiting.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_done_7"><text>Fair and square. Take it.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_2detector_done_8"><text>Speak to me again if you need something else.</text></string>

<string id="tex_bar_docent_detector3"><text>\nDocent needs two hands from controllers inhabiting the Swamps.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_0"><text>I've seen the message, have you been looking for me?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_1"><text>Our conversation about the device, do you remember it? I have some info about a couple of controllers. I hope you haven't changed your mind about our research?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_21"><text>Where have they seen them?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_22"><text>I don't have time right now, I'll come back later.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_3"><text>Here, it's not far. You've been to the Swamps before, right? The Hunters told me that they've seen some of their breed there.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_4"><text>So... What do you want from me this time?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_5"><text>Only two hands are needed to tune the detector. I think that should be enough.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_6"><text>How did controllers end up at the Swamps? It's a quiet place... or at least it was. Dogs and boars running about, tushkanos murmuring about something.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_7"><text>The device is being made precisely for that purpose - to understand mutant migration paths exactly. Can you imagine that?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_8"><text>You'd better imagine my reward. A controller is a dangerous creature, you can't just sneak up on it. I'll need a good rifle with a scope.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_9"><text>I'll help you with obtaining such a rifle. And also with ammo and medicine, as per usual. I'll even throw in little something extra. Deal?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_91"><text>Deal, mark those telepaths on my PDA.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_92"><text>I don't like this idea.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_11"><text>I've got their usual location marked in your PDA.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_12"><text>Suit yourself, I'll find someone else to take the job.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_start_13"><text>Take care... researcher.</text></string>

<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_0"><text>I've brought the hands</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_1"><text>Hands, whose hands?!</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_2"><text>Have you been drinking lately?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_3"><text>Ah, controller hands. Now I remember</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_4"><text>Take them, they're already starting to smell. They turned out to be especially fierce controllers.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_5"><text>Yeah, I asked the hunters to choose the most seasoned ones. They have the purest DNA, or so I've been told.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_6"><text>I've already heard about them being seasoned. Where's my reward?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_7"><text>I have a belt with 4 artifact slots, or, if you need it, I can give you a scope for a sniper rifle. Some stalker gave it to me as a deposit for my work. He promised to pay me after making some money, but I haven't seen him for a long time. He's probably dead already.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_81"><text>Are you trying to play me for a fool, Docent? Alright, give me the belt.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_82"><text>I want the scope, but I'm starting to dislike our partnership.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_91"><text>The belt, new and shiny. Quite a battery hog though.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_92"><text>Here, cool stuff. You can see a mosquito's leg in detail through it.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_3detector_done_10"><text>Take care... researcher.</text></string>

<string id="tex_bar_docent_detector4"><text>\nTwo hands from pseudogiants inhabiting Radar are needed to tune Docent's detector.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_0"><text>Barkeep said you've been missing me.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_1"><text>Marked One, where have you been? Do you remember our deal and the device? I have some info about a couple of pseudogiants. What do you think, are you still willing to participate in our research?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_21"><text>Where have they seen them?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_22"><text>I don't have time right now, I'll come back later.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_3"><text>In the Red Forest, near Radar. After disabling the Brain Scorcher the way is now relatively safe.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_4"><text>Safe?! How about you take me on a vacation there then?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_5"><text>Marked One, we are almost finished. Only some small details are left to work out.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_6"><text>Everything is a small detail to you. Do you realize that there's more dogs per square meter than rats in the entire Bar?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_7"><text>Yes, I understand. But nobody else would help me. You see, there's almost nobody left. Some Hunters have seen the pseudogiants from the hill, but were too cowardly to enter the forest.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_8"><text>More like the clever ones... What are you offering as a reward?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_9"><text>I've heard you've got a storage problem. I can rent my own stash to you for a small fee.  guarantee it's security.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_91"><text>Small, you say... Alright, deal, mark them on my PDA</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_92"><text>I don't like this idea.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_11"><text>I've marked their location on your PDA map</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_12"><text>Suit yourself, I'll find someone else to take the job.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_start_13"><text>Take care... researcher..</text></string>

<string id="bar_docent_4detector_done_0"><text>I've brought the hands for the device.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_done_1"><text>Hands, what for?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_done_2"><text>Have you already forgotten, Docent?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_done_3"><text>Ah, yes, good thing you're here to remind me.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_done_4"><text>Take them, they're already starting to smell. Those turned out to be really fierce pseudogiants.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_done_5"><text>Yeah, I asked the hunters to choose the most seasoned ones. They have the purest DNA, or so I've been told.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_done_6"><text>What's been our deal?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_done_7"><text>Your loot. Or its safety, to be more precise.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_done_8"><text>What a tricky partner you are, Docent. When will the device be ready? It will be interesting to see the results.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_done_9"><text>Hell, you are quick. It's science, brother. Maybe this week, maybe a bit later. I'll have to check the core functionality. Go on now, I'm busy.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_4detector_done_10"><text>Then go work, I'll leave you to it.</text></string>

<string id="bar_docent_5detector_0"><text>Docent, so how is the device?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_1"><text>Ah, Marked One. I've encountered a problem, that's why I called you</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_2"><text>I won't go anywhere, don't even ask me to.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_3"><text>I'm not asking you to go anywhere. Something is wrong with the damned device, maybe I miscalculated something, or they made an error. But there are no results from it yet.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_4"><text>What, was all this for nothing? How do I get my time, health and sanity back? That's not a proper way to do business.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_5"><text>I understand, but who could have expected this. They assured me that everything would come out right.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_6"><text>Docent, you might not live through the day when letting people down like that... your conscience will torture you to death.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_7"><text>Hold on now, no need to be hasty. I can partially compensate for your trouble. I have some info I found in some stalker's PDA. Honestly, I don't have anything else, I invested the rest of my money in this device.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_8"><text>Your honesty is very much appreciated. What info do you have?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_9"><text>A stash. Judging by the description, it's full of loot.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_10"><text>Yeah, and it's in the middle of nowhere, as usual. You know what Docent, screw you, your device, the mutants, and the Zone as well.</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_11"><text>What? Do you have some screws loose in your head?</text></string>
<string id="bar_docent_5detector_12"><text>Yes, I do have some screws loose in my head! Understood?!</text></string>

<!-- mikhalych_item_Tesla-->
<string id="tex_mikhalych_item"><text>\nMikhalych asked me to find the lost devices. I have to look for an abandoned military convoy, somewhere at the east of the Tesla zone.</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_start_0"><text>Why are you looking at me like that, what do you want?</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_start_1"><text>I have a little problem. If you help us, or rather myself, then I'll pay you well.</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_start_2"><text>What's the problem? And I'd like to know beforehand, what exactly do you mean by paying well?</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_start_3"><text>Professor Sakharov, that guy sitting in a tin can at Yantar, contacted me. The point is that two particularly valuable devices were lost in that goddamn Tesla zone.</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_start_4"><text>Understood. What about the reward?</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_start_5"><text>Alright, listen. You surely know that artifacts have different properties. Some are better, some are worse. For example, there's "Medusa" which radiate those roentgens like crazy, but protects against telepathy and who knows what else, and there's that radioactive... thing, that doesn't protect from anything. Although Medusa is always Medusa, even in Africa, and in the mainland they won't be able to tell which one is radioactive and which one isn't. It's more important here, in the Zone, for a simple stalker, if it protects your ass without any radiation.\nSee, that's where a business is born: if you need a good artifact, you come to me and give me two poor artifacts, and I give you a better one. Deal?</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_start_61"><text>If I agree, where do I find these devices for Sakharov? The Tesla zone isn't exactly the place to look under every bush for an entire day.</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_start_62"><text>Nah, I don't need it.</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_start_71"><text>They've been lost in sector 23. The approximate location is the military convoy in the eastern part of the Tesla zone. The devices aren't very heavy, about five kilograms each. I've already told several stalkers about this problem, but I think you have this... potential for the important jobs.</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_start_72"><text>That's unfortunate, but it's your call.</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_start_8"><text>I'll try to look for them, but I can't promise anything.</text></string>

<string id="mikhalych_item_done_0"><text>Mikhalych, I've found those goddamn "devices".</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_done_1"><text>I hope they aren't radioactive at least? I don't want any radiation here.</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_done_2"><text>No. But those "devices" look more like containers. Maybe there's something inside?</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_done_3"><text>Containers or not, what do you care? If there's something inside, let Sakharov examine it. Our job was just to find it, understand?</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_done_4"><text>Take them then, it's better to leave the scientists to their work.</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_done_5"><text>Yeah, they don't seem to be radioactive. Interesting, what could have been so important to take out from the Tesla zone that they needed an entire military convoy?</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_done_6"><text>So these really are containers?!</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_done_7"><text>That's not your business. Here, for your troubles, and you can bring me the artifacts. I will trade for them.</text></string>
<string id="mikhalych_item_done_8"><text>Not much... It's clear whose friend you are.</text></string>
<!-- finish -->