<string id="pda_krysyka_name"><text>Ratman's PDA</text></string>
<string id="mil_vasilev_name"><text>Unknown man</text></string>
<string id="pda_krysyka_desc"><text>According to Ratman, this is one of Borov's PDAs. But it doesn't turn on. It's broken. Who knows what secrets are hidden on it?</text></string>

<string id="marsh_treasure"><text>According to Frol, a warehouse with weapons was around here somewhere... Most likely it got looted a long time ago.</text></string>
<string id="vodka_rad"><text>Homemade vodka</text></string>
<string id="vodka_rad_descr"><text>There used to be this one "enterpreneur" in the Zone. Tried to sell cheap vodka. Now he's in the afterlife, regretting his greed.</text></string>
<string id="food_bread_rad"><text>Radioactive bread</text></string>
<string id="enc_food_bread_rad"><text>Used to be normal bread... Now it's radioactive... Can be consumed if you're tired of living.</text></string>

<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hey, bro, you doin' good? Wanna chat?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>Not bad, you? Chat about what?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>Not much, just talk shit over a drink.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>Well, sure, pour me one.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>Fuck off, I don't drink with just anyone. </text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Go fuck yourself then!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Bottoms up...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>Shit, we're out of nectar...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>Oo-oof... Good shit... Some salo would be great about now...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>So, bro... Hear an-n-ything interesting lately?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>I'll only tell this to you, bratan... I found a PDA on a corpse not long ago. Had some notes on it about a hidden stash. I'm too damn lazy to get it myself, and you look like an okay guy, so you can have it.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>What are you on about, man? There's nothing interesting around here, this ain't Rio-de-Zhytomyr... Nothing but boring shit around here! </text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>I'll go check it out if I have nothing else to do.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>Right, then. Call me if you have anything.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>How's life, man? Got time to chat?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>Sure thing... Kick back, relax.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>Seriously, I'd go for some proper meat right now. On skewers, and fried...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>Just pour the drinks, we'll find some meat, don't worry.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>Fuck off, I don't drink with just anyone. </text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Go fuck yourself then!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>Bottoms up, then. To our guys...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>Nah, man, if only I had some...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>To our guys, yeah...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>Hey, have anything interesting to tell, perhaps?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>Interesting, huh? Heard some talk at one of our meeting places, supposedly about an unlooted stash. I'm not going that far for it, I have enough dumbasses to deal with around here. If you can be bothered to go that far, go ahead and write down the coords.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>Catch yourself a little birdie to tell you interesting things...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>Nah, I can't be fucked, either, I'd leave it behind even if I were close by.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>Calm down, dumbass...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Hey guys! What's everyone babbling about?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>Hey, yourself, victim. Borov said to leave you be, but don't go looking for problems around here.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>It's so boring without vodka... You know, it's supper time in prison right now, they're serving macaroni!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>Don't jinx anyone, just focus on pouring drinks for the guys...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>Fuck off, I don't drink with just anyone. </text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Go fuck yourself then!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>Alright, bros. Cheers! </text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>Sure, gonna talk with Borov first and then pour us a couple.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>Mmmm, respect! Should have said so right away...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>Hear anything new, an-n-ything interesting lately?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>New? Yesterday me and the guys pinned down three dutyers. One minute they're lounging around all cool on their posts and the next thing you know they're begging: "guys, don't do it, you don't have to kill us"... "I'll show you a stash instead"... A stash, sure, think they can just bullshit us, quietly slink away, and then roll in with their whole gang? Heh... And he goes: "the stash is really close", what a dumbass, huh? Ah, fuck all this... This stash of his... Hang on... Oh! There it is! Imagine that...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>New? What could possibly be new here? Shit's all the same.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>Ha, it takes half a day to get there. They were definitely bullshitting.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>See ya. Stop by when you have a forty.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>Whoa! Who's this I'm seeing! How long's it been?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>Get lost, don't you see I'm tired after yesterday...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>Let's get your health fixed up then...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>We're out of everything. Ran out yesterday. Totally fucking empty.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>Fuck off, I don't drink with just anyone. </text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Go fuck yourself then!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>I always keep a little stashed away for health reasons. Bottoms up!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>Opa... I'm dry as of late, too.</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>Da-a-amn, that's generous of you...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>What's the word around here? Any places that still have loot around?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>You bet! But keep your voice down. I recently saw some of Borov's lackeys hiding away a stash. I'm not about to grab it myself, we're strict about that around here, you're risking to wake up with a knife in your back, but if you sneak in and out, no one will suspect a thing. And stop by again when you're around, we'll discuss a couple other things. Alright?</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>Borov's got all the profitable places for himself, we get scraps...</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>You got it!</text></string>
<string id="bandit_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>Alright, I'm off, bye.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hey, bro... How goes it?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>Not bad, I guess. You wanted something, or?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>Not really...It's so quiet out here, I'm thinking, why not sit down and have a drink to boost our health a little.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>Health is important, pour me one, I suppose.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>I've got no problems with my health, I'm not drinking today.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Alright, just a small drink.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>If only someone poured me one...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>It's strong... Damn... Some salo would be great.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>Yeah... Hits goo-o-od... Any chance you know anything interesting?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>Not long ago Wolf and I were pulling a stalker out of an anomaly... Rather, what was left of him... Yeah... He had a note with some coordinates on him. Supposedly that's where his stash is... But Wolf said to stay clear of that place. Here's the coordinates, write them down, and tell me later if it was anything interesting. Deal?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>Nope, I've not been around for long, haven't been far yet... Stop by in a week, maybe I'll find something out by then.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>Alright... I'll check it out...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>Alright, we'll talk more when I have free time.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>Hey, how's the stalker's life?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>Hey, Marked One... It's...okay. Going slowly, but surely.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>Perhaps a splash of vodka would do it? To boost your health. </text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>That would be great! Share some, if you're so charitable.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>I've got no problems with my health, I'm not drinking today.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>There we go, a hundred-fifty grams each, for bravery...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>Hang on, I just need to see Sid first...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>Damn... (cough cough) What do they brew this out of? Old furniture wood? Nearly barfed it all back out...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>Out here, you never know, it could be anything... Got anything interesting to tell?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>A couple stalkers came to see Sid not long ago... I was asleep nearby. Well, not exactly asleep - with one eye open, rather... They wanted to buy some of his equipment, on credit, so to speak... They told him about a stash with great loot, they even described the place... But Sid didn't sell them anything, what a tightwad, huh? I thought I'd go look, but can't quite get it together yet. Here's the place, see? If you find anything, don't forget about me, alright? </text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>What can I say... This is the Zone, I wouldn't mind getting out of here.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>If it's anything worthwhile, I won't forget.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>We'll get out of here, some day...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Why are you so glum?.. Need any help, maybe?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>What's there to be happy about? It's so dull around here, almost makes you wanna shove your head in a noose.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>In that case, let's have a drink. Not to get drunk, but to improve the mood...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>A-a-a-h, sure! Maybe it'll help...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>My mood's fine, I'm not drinking today...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>There... Hold it steady... To HOPE!</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>No way! I remember for sure I had a bottle... Now it's GONE!</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>To good old hope... Thank you, looks like there's still decent men around.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>I hear that you can find some loot nearby, know anything about that?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>Yeah, they're saying there's a stash with some loot, and not too far from here... But no one that went to check it out came back. Let me show you on the map: right here...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>Nope, haven't heard... I don't really keep an ear out for rumors.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>I'm not going out of my way for it, but I'll check it out if I happen to be nearby.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>All the better. The less you know - the better you sleep...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>Hey, friend... Can we talk?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>Hey... What's this about?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>Let's sit down for a bit, chat over some good refreshments...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>The food's on me, pour us some, what're you waiting for?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>I don't have time to talk, going on a raid soon...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>There she is, my dearest, clear as a teardrop!</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>We have food, sure... But nothing to drink...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>Whoo-oh, that's good! Hits you right down to the ass! Good stuff!</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>I hear ya... Anything going on in the Zone?</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>Day before yesterday, I was sitting around with some army soldiers, emptied a few bottles with them... They come here pretty often from Agroprom, Sid supplies them with vodka. They talked about how they caught a zombified stalker and, well, as you can imagine, he's all mumbling and moaning and grabbing for his rifle. The commander ordered to take him alive, send him to the eggheads outside of the Zone - for experiments, yeah... If you ask me, better to put a bullet through his head and get it over with... What was I on about? Oh yeah, so, this zombie had a drawing on his arm, like a tattoo, but not a real one, more like someone carved it out with a knife... Like a map or something. Their commander checked it for clues and it seems that there's a stash with loot not far from here. Approximately here...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>Lots of things going on, with anomalies, with monsters, too much to talk about in one go. Stop by later, we'll talk more...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>Yeah, better to go out quick... without suffering...</text></string>
<string id="neitral_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>I'll stop by, we'll talk.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hey, bratan. How are things around here?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>Mutants tend to mess with us sometimes... Otherwise I guess things are alright.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>Care to grab a drink? To becoming acquainted? Or does brass not allow it?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>What brass? Our warrant officer, Prapor, served before, he understands that you can't go without it in the Zone. So don't worry, pour us some. </text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>Brass has nothing to do with it, I'm just not in the mood...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Well then! To good people!..</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>I'd pour you one, but I used up my last forty for health reasons.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>To us, that is! Eat something with it, here's some sausage.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>Thank you... What's the word around here? Any news, maybe?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>No unusual news. But you hear about Max Liuber? Bandits from Dark Valley caught him and his friend... Bullet - Liuber's friend - followed their trail... But before that he said that Max's friend shared some info about a map with pointers to a place with some hidden loot... Here! Bullet tried to ask someone to go get it, but brass wouldn't allow it, saying there's already too few fighters left on the post. Anyway, here's the place, take what's in there so bandits don't get to it instead.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>Don't think I've heard anything unusual, just the same old...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>Fine, I'll take it.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>Well, buh-bye, see you later.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>Greetings, soldier!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>Hey, yourself... Where'd you come from?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>Me, I'm just slowly exploring the Zone... How about a hundred grams?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>Not a question! Two hundred grams never did anyone any harm...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>Here, have two hundred and fifty, no appetizers.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>Let me just haul some artefacts to Barkeep and I'll be back...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>Hah, that hits pretty good... Why would I need appetizers for nectar like this...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>That's true, wouldn't want to ruin a good thing... Tell me something interesting...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>Bes visited a couple days ago, good man, even though he's a Loner... No offense, alright? We helped him out with some ammo, talked about this and that... He didn't have anything valuable on him, so he told us about a stash. Didn't have any loot in it, though, but it did seem like someone hides their goods there pretty often. Scout if out if you're feeling like it, see who it belongs to... </text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>What's there to say? This is the Zone, and if not for us, this disease would have spread to the entire world by now.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>I'll try to scout it out...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>Well, see you later, savior of the world...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Hey, man, your face looks familiar, have we met before?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>Who knows, I only remember the ones I'm friendly with.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>Well, how about a drink, not to get drunk, but to friendship...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>Well well, I think I might be recalling you after all... Sure, pour me one!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>There... Hold it steady... To Friendship!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>No way! I remember having a bottle! Now it's GONE!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>To reliable friends! To those who'll watch your back even in the Zone!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>I hear that you can find some loot nearby, know anything about that?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>Didn't tell this to anyone, but I'll tell you, as a friend. There's some clues leading to a hidden spot... Accidentally found out about it. Maybe it's empty, but maybe it's got tons of loot. If you're a real friend, I assume you'll share?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>No, haven't heard anything... Everyone's gathered up all the loot that's nearby, and only Strelok knows what's further up there...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>Of course, what are you talking about! Anything for a friend...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>Strelok? I see... I have a couple questions for him.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>Hi, can we talk, if you don't mind?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>Sure, sit if you want... What's up?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>How's about a splash of vodka?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>The snacks are on me, pour us some, what're you waiting for?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>Keep the glasses steady so I don't pour over the edge.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>We have snacks, sure... But nothing to drink...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>Oo-o-of! That greased up the old gears.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>Doesn't it get boring sitting around here all day?</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>Not really, what's there to be bored of? Barkeep sends over food as pay for guarding the place... Loners stop by often and share the latest news... And there's always things to shoot at. \nKhohma: The bandits have been getting bold lately, always setting up ambushes... For example, we had this happen: some guy's lying there, pretending to be a wounded stalker, sending SOS signals to every radio frequency, when suddenly a couple burers stumble upon him... This "wounded" guy, as soon as he hears their screams, jumps up and starts running without even looking where he's going. Runs right at us and hits the checkpoint gate - smack! There's noise, and fuss, and stench - this fan of easy money crapped himself so hard it got all up to his ears... Then he kept trembling and promising riches for everybody, saying he's got a stash hidden, and showed it on the map... What a weirdo, I swear... No one here's gonna risk their ass for some stash. We are a bulwark! Protecting the world from all this unnatural vermin! If you're interested, here's the note he gave us...</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>Sure, it gets boring, but at least you feel like you're part of a cause - protecting the World from unnatural vermin!</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>Good one... I'll take a look if I get the chance, but I think it's all bullshit.</text></string>
<string id="dolg_garb_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>Wouldn't want to distract a hero, then...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hey, bro... How's life?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>Fucking sick of bandits! They just keep coming! My nerves can't take much more! </text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>Blow off some steam... Let's relax a little...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>I'm not mad, just that we haven't had decent booze in a while... Pour me some, if you're offering...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Let's drink to tomorrow, to seeing another day at all!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>I'm all out right now. Gotta see a trader, stock up...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>Cheers! To death of old age!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>There... That eases the burden a little... What's the word around here?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>Everyone tries to keep their thoughts to themselves. This is the Zone, brother... But I did hear that a couple guys stashed away some of their things when returning from one of the military outposts... I thought of getting the stash myself, but doesn't seem likely anymore... So you can have it, if you want, get some use out of it before it disappears completely. A few days ago those guys I mentioned got killed during a bandit raid. A real shame, they were good stalkers, friends of ours...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>Everyone tries to keep their thoughts to themselves. This is the Zone, brother... Even friends don't plan anything in advance... So no one gets jinxed...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>Yeah... A lot of good people leave us...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>That's for sure. Alright, friend, until tomorrow...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>I heard shooting here, what was that about?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>We're shooting to keep the enemies on their toes. And ourselves, too...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>Let's grab two-fifty grams each, for bravery?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>Yeah, pour me one!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>Take two-fifty! To be sure!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>Hold on a minute, I'll just look around first, see what the situation is...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>Eugh! That's nasty. Strong, though...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>Heh, what were you expecting? Lemonade? Hear about anything interesting?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>Bes and his boys killed a dozen marauders near the swamp, then I went to check it out... Sure enough, wild animals did quite a number on the bodies, it was a grisly sight... I took a closer look and in the middle of all the slaughter I saw something shiny. Used a stick to take it out and it turned out to be a bottle, really small, about fifty grams, probably a souvenir. Mm-yeah... Seems like the guy swallowed it when he sensed danger. This bottle had a piece of paper in it, with a map to a stash inside. Here's the map, maybe you could reach the stash. I couldn't...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>Everything's as usual, some guy died in an anomaly, another guy got shot, third guy just vanished without a trace... Such are our "interesting" news...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>If I manage to reach it, half of it's yours.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>Right then, keep it together... See you.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Hi, mind exchanging a couple words?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>What's the point in standing around and yapping? Not unless it's something important...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>Maybe we could grab a drink, to get acquainted? Doesn't sound too bad, right?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>I don't have anything to drink... If you do, though, then let's see it, don't just run your mouth...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>I don't want any right now. Not in the mood...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>I sure do! Cheers, to kindred spirits!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>Sorry, friend, I'm all out, too...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>You talk too much... Drinking, just like living, should be done quietly...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>Aren't you the philosopher! Well, go ahead then, enlighten me on how life should be lived...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>Everyone lives their life according to themselves, and you can't learn to live another person's life... Take Lucky Lyovka, for instance, you've probably heard of him, right? Used to brag about how lucky he is, how women are into him, and how all the monsters steer clear of him... He didn't live for the present day, he hid away his things, planned out stashes. Couldn't convince him to grab a drink or unwind a little, he saved all his artefacts, didn't sell them to the local traders, thought he'd sell them outside the Zone and start rolling in the dough... And where is he now? Not even a lock of hair's left of him after he got dissolved in the "Jelly". Now a bunch of other "lucky" guys are looking for those stashes. If you ask me, nothing good can come out of the loot in them, and that loot is likely useless for people like me, who live only for today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>What's the point in englightening you? If you have a path in life, you follow it, if not - you won't just be handed one.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>Maybe you're right, but I think one should prepare for the day ahead...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>That's you destiny then, I suppose. But I believe in the human spirit...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>How goes it, friend?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>So far, so good. Bit boring, though...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>Wanna grab a bit to drink? To improve the mood?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>The bottle's on you, everything else is on me...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>Nah, get lost...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>I'm down for that! Get the glasses...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>I have everything else too, but no bottle...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>Damn, she's good! Burns the whole gut!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>Tell me something interesting...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>Something interesting? Hmm... What could I possibly lie about... Ah, whatever! Fine, I'll tell it as it is... You know Yurik? Scrawny newbie, tried to tag along with seasoned stalkers to go looking for loot. He was a lightweight on the booze too, drinks a sip but acts like he downed an entire bucket. Sat around with us yesterday, ran his mouth... Got all revved up saying he's gonna one-up the seasoned stalkers because he knows where some impressive stash is hidden. We laughed at him, but he started pointing at the screen of his PDA, where the stash is marked on the map. No one believed him, of course, where does a snot-nosed coward from Cordon like him know such info... Allegedly, there's some stash right there... Would you believe him?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>I'm so exhausted I can barely turn my tongue, I can tell you something tomorrow...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>Nah, I wouldn't believe that. Yurik is one hell of a liar.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_garb_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>Until tomorrow then, friend...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hi, how are things around here?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>It's fun around here, if you want you can head to the Bar, or chat around with dutyers, or place bets at the arena. A lot of rumors floating around, the Bar's almost at the center of the Zone, after all...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>How about taking a drink? To getting acquainted.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>Not a bad idea... Pour us some, we'll go to the arena afterwards for some excitement, tickle our nerves so to speak...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Cheers, to keeping our spirits high!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>I'll run to the 100 Rads bar for a bottle... Wait here!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>Go on, then...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>Any rumors floating around? Anyone saying anything interesting?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>Lots of things, I guess... Supposedly there's a teleporter that leads straight to the Monolith, though I've heard that about at least ten different locations. A new type of monster showed up - hits you with electricity, now that's some shit... Duty and Freedom are still fighting over the Zone, all you ever hear is about how one faction killed the other, or the other way around, but what is there to fight over and try to divide up? There's enough of the Zone for everyone... Not long ago they caught a freedomer and took him into their basement to re-educate him. Some psychiatrists... Well that freedomer tossed something into the bushes, later I went and looked, found his PDA, and it had stash coordinates. Here. Let's go together, see what's in it? I think it's located around here...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>Come to the Bar later in the evening, our guys are gonna gather up, we can sit and have a chat... You can hear plenty of interesting things, just don't forget to keep the booze flowing...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>That's pretty far, I'm going the opposite way right now...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>Alright, I'll come by.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>Hey, man. How's life?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>Bursting with excitement... More like my head is about to burst... What do you want?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>What're you so angry about? Let's have a drink to improve the mood?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>I'm sick of everything! Let's drink...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>Hey! Screw everything! Bottoms up!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>Better if I leave you be...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>Well, alright. At least they still haven't forgotten how to make decent vodka.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>Yep, clear like a Komsomol member's teardrop... What are you sick of, anyway?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>No one but assholes around... You mean people well, and they smear you in shit in return. I found this stash, thought I'd take this one asshole with me so someone would cover my back. But this pest quietly fucked off, and stole everything from my backpack... Ugh... Some people... Assholes! Maybe you could get ahead of him? Here's where the stash is...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>There's plenty of douchebags around, that's for sure, can't trust anyone... All they want is to fuck with you.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>I'll see if I can. I'll try to restore your faith in people.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>You're an angry guy, I'm leaving.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Hey, bratan, have we met before?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>Your face looks familiar too, I think, what's-your-name?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>Call me Marked One, everyone does...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>Okay, Marked One it is. So, a drink to becoming acquainted? Have any on you?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>Alright, Marked One. I'd drink to becoming acquainted, but I'm not in the mood right now...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>Sure do! Here! It's damn strong.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>No, I don't have any... Had to trade my whole supply for ammunition...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>Hah! It's strong, that's for sure! Well then, Marked One my brother, seems like there's now two more good people in the Zone.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>I hear that you can find some loot nearby, know anything about that?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>Well, since you're a good person, and good people should help each other, I'll tell you this, Marked One... Zombies have been stumbling into the base pretty often as of late, there's a mystery for you - all the entrances to the base are guarded by Duty, not even a mouse can slink past, but these things keep showing up anyway. They're always mumbling something, stretching their arms out... It's creepy! Last night I was relaxing all cultured-like - Barman, the bastard, won't let me put my drinks on credit anymore, what a cheapskate, huh? Anyway, I started falling asleep, but felt something, some stench and a feeling of heaviness, I opened my eyes - and there he is, our pal the walking corpse. I froze in place, couldn't move my arms or legs... Not out of fear, of course, just out of surprise... And the dead guy mumbled something, I tried to make it out and heard numbers, the same thing repeated over and over. I closed my eyes, then opened them - and he was gone... Only the stench remained. And the numbers kept repeating in my head, so I checked them out - they looked like coordinates. But it's pretty far from here... So that's how the story goes, bro.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>All the easy to reach places have already been looted... You have to go towards the center of the Zone, they say that's where the Klondike is.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>Sounds like you might've had some bad bootleg vodka, where'd you get it?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>Klondike, you say? Yeah, sure...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>Why so sad, friend?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>Well, just thinking I gotta leave the Zone... It gets worse and worse every day. The monsters are getting more dangerous and angry, the weather is shit, anomalies everywhere, and worst of it all - people are turning into animals...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>Alright, forget about that! Let's have a drink instead...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>Okay, let's, but is there anything to drink?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>I wouldn't have offered if I didn't have any...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>Ah, hell! I swear I had a bottle! Must have been stolen!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>Err, it's not Chardonnay, but it's not bad either!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>Why don't you go looking for artefacts?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>It's a long story... You in a hurry? I had a friend, Seryoga Earless, we used to go to dangerous raids together all the time... One time we got all the way to the Brain Scorcher, saw those phantoms out there, and that's not all... \nPour me a bit more... Ye-a-ah, Seryoga... His ear got shot off in Chechnya, hence the nickname. Can't count how many times we've covered each other's backs... On our last raid we stumbled on a pseudogiant, it's not the most dangerous creature if you don't face it head-on like an idiot. But it just so happens, the beast slams its hand on the ground and Seryoga gets thrown back, well, no further than half a meter, and lands with his entire body straight into the "Jelly"... His face, and hands... Everything... Meat was sliding off his skull... And he was conscious, too... Pour me some more, my soul's burning up... I abandoned him there... And I left my soul there, too. We left a stash there, but I won't take it, I don't want to... If you find it, pay your respects to Seryoga.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>I can't... The Zone broke me... Another day or two and I'll start preparing to leave...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>I will if I find it...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_bar_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>That's probably for the best... I think...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_0"><text>Hello, can we talk?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_1"><text>Hello, why not? I see you're not one of those shitheads...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_2"><text>No, I'm not one of them... Let's grab a hundred grams each?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_3"><text>Hmm... Not a bad thought... Pour me some...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_41"><text>Cheers, to getting acquainted...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_42"><text>Damn, I'm all out...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_5"><text>To getting acquainted... Whew, where'd you find this... This is some nasty crap...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_6"><text>It's not Smirnoff, that's for sure! What's the word in the Zone?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_71"><text>Well, I've heard some things here and there... Allegedly there's some great stashes left over from stalkers that died. There's hidden faction stashes, but I haven't heard of anyone finding one. I found a PDA completely by accident, and a stash is marked on its map, I can share it with you... I'm not likely to go there myself...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_73"><text>Come to the Bar later in the evening, our guys are gonna gather up, we can sit and have a chat... You can hear plenty of interesting things, just don't forget to keep the booze flowing...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_81"><text>Thanks, I'll check it out if I'm ever nearby.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_1_dialog_82"><text>Alright, I'll come by.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_0"><text>Hey, man. How's life?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_1"><text>Bursting with excitement...More like my head is about to burst... What do you want?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_2"><text>What're you so angry about? Let's have a drink to improve the mood?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_3"><text>I'm sick of everything! Let's drink...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_41"><text>Hey! Screw everything! Bottoms up!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_42"><text>Better if I leave you be...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_5"><text>Well, alright. At least they still haven't forgotten how to make decent vodka.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_6"><text>Yep, clear like a Komsomol member's teardrop... What are you sick of, anyway?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_71"><text>No one but assholes around... You mean people well, and they smear you in shit in return. I found this stash, thought I'd take this one asshole with me so someone would cover my back. But this pest quietly fucked off, and stole everything from my backpack... Ugh... Some people... Assholes! Maybe you could get ahead of him? Here's where the stash is...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_73"><text>There's enough douchebags around, that's for sure, can't trust anyone... All they want is to fuck with you.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_81"><text>I'll see if I can. I'll try to restore your faith in people.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_2_dialog_82"><text>You're an angry guy, I'm leaving.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_0"><text>Hey, bratan, have we met before?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_1"><text>Your face looks familiar too, I think, what's-your-name?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_2"><text>Call me Marked One, everyone does...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_3"><text>Okay, Marked One it is. So, a drink to becoming acquainted? Have any on you?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_31"><text>Alright, Marked One. I'd drink to becoming acquainted, but I'm not in the mood right now...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_41"><text>Sure do! Here! Strong like a sailor's cursing...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_42"><text>No, I don't have any... Had to trade my whole supply for ammunition...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_5"><text>Hah! It's strong, that's for sure! Well then, Marked One my brother, seems like there's now two more good people in the Zone.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_6"><text>I hear that you can find some loot nearby, know anything about that?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_71"><text>I was in Yantar not long ago, figured I'd check out what the eggheads are up to... Didn't go too far, my brain wouldn't really handle it... Saw those poor bastards out there - the zombified stalkers. They shoot like Voroshilov sharpshooters, though! How's that even possible? Their brains don't work anymore, right? One of them was lying on the ground nearly dead so I tried to search him and then - oh man! Some gross crap squirts out of him, I nearly died from the poison... Anyway, he had a map to a stash on him... I won't risk going there, but I can share it with you.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_73"><text>All the easy to reach places have already been looted... You have to go towards the center of the Zone, they say that's where the Klondike is.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_81"><text>Alright, I'll risk it!..</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_3_dialog_82"><text>Klondike, you say? Yeah, sure...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_0"><text>Why so sad, friend?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_1"><text>Well, just thinking I gotta leave the Zone... It gets worse and worse every day. The monsters are getting more dangerous and angry, the weather is shit, anomalies everywhere, and worst of it all - people are turning into animals...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_2"><text>Alright, forget about that! Let's have a drink instead...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_3"><text>Okay, let's, but is there anything to drink?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_41"><text>I wouldn't have offered if I didn't have any...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_42"><text>Ah, hell! I swear I had a bottle! Must have been stolen!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_5"><text>Err, it's not Chardonnay, but it's not bad either!</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_6"><text>Why don't you go looking for artefacts?</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_71"><text>It's a long story... You in a hurry? I had a friend, Seryoga Earless, used to go to dangerous raids together all the time... One time we got all the way to the Brain Scorcher, saw those phantoms out there, and that's not all... \nPour me a bit more... Ye-a-ah, Seryoga... His ear got shot off in Chechnya, hence the nickname. Can't count how many times we've covered each other's backs... On our last raid we stumbled on a pseudogiant, it's not the most dangerous creature if you don't face it head-on like an idiot. But it just so happens, the beast slams its hand on the ground and Seryoga gets thrown back, well, no further than half a meter, and lands with his entire body straight into the "Jelly"... His face, and hands... Everything... Meat was sliding off his skull... And he was conscious, too... Pour me some more, my soul's burning up... I abandoned him there... And I left my soul there, too. We left a stash there, but I won't take it, I don't want to... If you find it, pay your respects to Seryoga.</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_73"><text>I can't... The Zone broke me... Another day or two and I'll start preparing to leave...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_81"><text>I will if I find it...</text></string>
<string id="stalk_sim_treasure_4_dialog_82"><text>That's probably for the best... I think...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_0"><text>Heya, bratan. How goes it?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_1"><text>Couldn't be better... We got some crazy grass delivered not long ago, I was in a whole other world for 3 straight days... Too bad we ran out of it now...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_2">
<text>Well... Yeah... That sucks. How about a hundred grams instead?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_3"><text>What kinda question is that?! You got any?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_41"><text>I always have some for an occasion like this!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_42"><text>That's the problem, I don't have any...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_5"><text>(sigh) It vanished, and I didn't even notice.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_6"><text>Did you hear? Couple days ago some stalker showed up at the Bar, saying he emptied out some important merc's stash. He was all happy, telling everyone about how he picked up the merc's PDA somewhere around here at the Warehouses... The next day he disappeared and no one's seen him since then, seems like the mercs might have disposed of him... So there's that.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_71"><text>It's all the same old shit... We shoo these mercs around like they're cockroaches. On the other hand, we arranged this raid on the Duty base, it turned into a real war - it was pretty terrifying, but we couldn't break through because an emission started right then, a strong one, too... My brain started melting and I stumbled over some dutyer's corpse, got a glimpse of his PDA, and quickly grabbed it... We had to hold out over at the Wild Territory... Ended up bunkering down in some garage until the emission ended... When we returned to our base, I inspected the PDA and found a mark to a stash on the map, ri-i-igh here. I didn't have time to check it, so you can have it, here you go...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_73"><text>Screw him. Shouldn't have been showing off. Maybe then he would've lived longer. Anyway, I'm getting kinda sleepy... Come back later!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_81"><text>Right... I'll check it out sometime, thanks. See you later...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_1_dialog_82"><text>I'll stop by, don't doubt it.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_0"><text>Heya, friend! How's life?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_1"><text>Kinda crappy, no one wants to join and reinforce our ranks... Maybe you wanna join in? Life would get a bit calmer if you did...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_2">
<text>Well, I might be considering it... How about we share a bottle, to getting to know one another?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_3"><text>(sigh) If only there were more generous people like you... I just so happen to have half a kilo of sausage saved for just such an occasion. Get the elixir out!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_41"><text>There she is, authentic Ukrainian "Cossacks". Hold the glass!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_42"><text>I was ju-ust about to pay Screw a visit, hang on, if he has any left, I'll borrow some.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_5"><text>Brrr... My liver won't be happy... But you get points in my book!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_6"><text>So, friend? (hic)... What's ha-happening around here anyway?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_71"><text>Well, not long ago Lukash requested that someone check the Barrier... Said there's some trouble... So I grab those monkeys that are sitting by the campfire, there, see em? So we go to the barrier and there's a massive zombie attack going on! 50 or something of them... We only lost our sniper, even though I thought all of us would be put down. The zombified are lively bastards, want it or not, you have to go and finish them off... So I approached one of them, and he started mumbling some numbers over and over, so I "helped" the poor fella out and put him out of his misery. When I got back, I realized that the numbers were coordinates, but for what? They point right here...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_73"><text>What's there to happen at our place? Oh yeah, we got a new plan brought it recently - crazy stuff! If you wanna buy, go see Chef, he knows where to find it. And you should stop by more often for a chat.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_81"><text>Those zombies are always mumbling something. Don't pay too much attention.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_2_dialog_82"><text>Well, til next time! I've gotta go.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_0"><text>Hey, guys! Mind if I join?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_1"><text>Heya, Marked One! Move over, guys, give some space over to a respectable stalker.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_2"><text>Thank you for the hospitality. How about a drink?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_3"><text>Now that's what I'm talking about! We've got some shashlyk going on the fire just for that! So, where's the good stuff?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_41"><text>I've always got some on me. Here!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_42"><text>Where'd I put it?.. Must've lost it somewhere... Wait, I'll just run over to Bootlegger.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_5"><text>Brrr... Where'd you get this? Tell me the place - I'll start buying from nowhere but there from now on!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_6"><text>Yeah... You said it, it's one of the best ones that I ever drank! I found it in a stash nearby...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_71"><text>Listen, maybe it's our Bootlegger that hid it away for a special occasion? We were drinking together once and he accidentally let slip that he tends to go relax and blow off some steam ri-i-ight here. He's our tasting specialist, you see! How about you go check it out? Then we can continue the banquet!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_73"><text>Too bad, I would have bought crates of that vodka, great stuff! Well, if you have any more - stop by!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_81"><text>Yeah... Your Bootlegger guy's probably a champion drinker in the Zone... Well, see you...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_3_dialog_82"><text>Of course I'll stop by... Well, good luck!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_0"><text>Hi! What got you all upset?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_1"><text>Hi, Marked One. How else am I supposed to feel? There's no artefacts, no women, no vodka...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_2"><text>That's where you're wrong... I've got a forty lying around here somewhere...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_3"><text>Why didn't you say so right away? Make yourself comfortable, share what's in that backpack of yours. I've got a couple glasses just here.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_41"><text>Now where'd I put it? Ah, there it is, right at the bottom! Let's drink, to women, and to artefacts!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_42"><text>Where is... where'd I?... Wait here a minute, I'll run over to this one place, and then we'll have something to boost our health with.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_5"><text>You've got one hell of an arsenal... More impressive than ours... The glasses are too small. Well, let's drink to the ladies!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_6"><text>Cheers! Who-oh, hits goods! What's the word around here?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_71"><text>Well, not long ago a group was sent out, myself included, to the Dark Valley, to scout out any possible direct paths from there to the Warehouses. You must understand, we're caged up in here - Duty on one side, and the Brain Scorcher on the other. Anyway, we're out late in the evening and suddenly we see this image: some bandit out in the distance running around faster than a bullet... well, we get confused to say the least. Seems like he noticed us and changed direction, our jaws dropped and we're thinking, who's this Rambo? Then our sharp-eyed guy Roman tells us: "He's not running around there alone", Roman had night vission goggles on, you see. We take a closer look, and he's right... the air behind the bandit looks all distorted. He runs closer towards us by like 20 meters, and then we realize that shit's real bad - there's 4 bloodsuckers behind him! We had to put everyone down, including the bandit. He must have been just some lackey. We found a mark on his map's PDA, right here, without any notes or anything. The poor bandit bastard's pants were all brown - one hell of a mess. But I imagine anyone would have shat himself in his place.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_73"><text>You can always hear screaming not too far away in the distance. Fucking scary. But if you're looking for anything specific, I don't really keep up with what goes on here.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_81"><text>That guy sure didn't have the luckiest of days. Well, one more drink, and then I have to get going.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_4_dialog_82"><text>Sure, one more, and I'm going to bed, so tired today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_0"><text>Hi, guys!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_1"><text>Don't scream like that, this place is horrifying... it doesn't like being treated with disrespect. Stop prancing around so much, sit down. What'd you want?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_2"><text>Just thought I'd grab a drink with some decent men.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_3"><text>Well, that wouldn't hurt, since we've frozen our asses off by now.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_41"><text>Here, have some.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_42"><text>Actually, guys, I was hoping you'd be the ones treating me. Alright then, I'll run to the base and grab a bottle.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_5"><text>Respect for not letting us die of the cold... We're just sitting here, waiting for our guys... Waiting... They went to the village to clear out the bloodsucker lair... Seems like we won't be seeing them again... A real shame about the guys...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_6"><text>Mm-hm, even the hair on my ass is standing on end. Even vodka isn't helping the fear.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_71"><text>Oh, you touched upon on a sacred subject. So many legends are told about this place. Before the emission in 2006 this village used to look like the rookie village at Cordon, and my brother lived here. Everything was so quiet and peaceful... Until an emission hit so hard that barely anyone survived... Everyone was screaming... Waves of mutants rushed in from the direction of the Barrier, one after another. The emission lasted 10-15 minutes, but it seemed like a whole 3 hours, many people lost their friends then, and the next day we were sent to retrieve the dead and bury them, but we would have done that even without anyone asking us to. I found my brother... My own brother, he was lying in a basement, it was a pitiful sight. I took his weapon, look how shiny it still is, and his PDA. His PDA had only one mark on its map, right here, and a note that was addressed to me, but that's personal.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_73"><text>Lots of things happen around here... Either way, don't come here too often - this place is a real zoo of the Zone. There's bloodsuckers, and burers, and controllers, and dogs, and even chimeras come visit once in a while...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_81"><text>Damn, my condolences. Well, let's grab one last drink, I've got plenty of work to do.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_5_dialog_82"><text>Thanks for the tip, but we'll see each other again.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_0"><text>Hey, friend. Got any chow?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_1"><text>I do, what of it?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_2"><text>And do you have any drinks?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_3"><text>That's a no.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_41"><text>There, see? What would we do without each other? We've already got a picnic going here... here's your glass! What shall we drink to?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_42"><text>That's a shame, I don't have any either.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_5"><text>Teamwork, that's for sure. Let's drink to there always being people like you, and to them always finding people like me! Well, cheers! Oo-of, that's strong!</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_6"><text>You said it... Burns a little! Hey, maybe you know something I don't?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_71"><text>Well, bratan, you've probably been all over the Zone yourself, no? Do you know anything about the Dead City? No? That's where the Mercenaries' main base is. They took me hostage about half a year ago. Everything was by the killers' rules - bag on your head, pistolwhipped to the head, and they're driving me in an unknown direction... They brought me in and started interrogating me on how to quietly get into our base... I didn't tell them anything, of course. They left me in a cage overnight. There were two other guys next to me. One of them reminded me of you, by the way... We talked about how to escape, and all that. I noticed there was some map of the Zone at their base... with some dots on them, I can only remember one of them now: I think it was around here somewhere... then they dragged me out and hit me over the head with a pistol again and I woke up in the car with a hood over my head. They pushed me out of the car and told me to stand at the edge of a cliff, saying, like, what's your last wish and all... and then, to my luck, an emission starts... I had to jump. It turned out to be some swamp, and in the middle of the swamp was an old train wagon, so I waited there for the emission to end. Turns out they brought me to Agroprom... I barely got home... Told everyone here - no one believed me because I was drunk when I told them, but you understand, how couldn't I be, after surviving that...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_73"><text>Oh, how would I know? I'm here all day, they stationed me here a week ago, so I haven't seen anything interesting. Come back later, maybe I'll find something out.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_81"><text>Interesting, it's a miracle that you survived. Farewell.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_6_dialog_82"><text>Okay, I'll stop by sometime. See you later.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_0"><text>Why are you so pale?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_1"><text>It's so damn cold...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_2"><text>Why don't you get warmed up?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_3"><text>If only I had something to get warmed up with...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_31"><text>Not feeling like it today...</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_91"><text>Suit yourself.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_41"><text>I'll help you out with that! Here! What shall we drink to?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_42"><text>And here I am freezing... Wondering if anyone would help me get warm.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_5"><text>Let's drink to there being something to drink tomorrow! Oo-of, it's strong. Here, eat some sausage along with it.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_6"><text>Thanks. Listen, where does one find loot around here?</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_71"><text>Everyone's got trouble with that right now. They say there's loot behind the barrier, but it's dangerous to stick your head in there. I'm speaking from experience - I was broke and owed a lot of people, so circumstances forced me to head to the Barrier. So I went... nothing around me but silence... then I saw something moving in front of me so I hid behind a rock. I tripped and fell, and ended up face to face with an old acquaintance of mine who disappeared long ago, except by then he was halfway decomposed. Makes me wanna barf when I remember it. He was an authoritative stalker, had himself an AS-VAL. I took his backpack, figured he doesn't need it anymore. Just as I got up I saw Monolith soldiers talking to the zombified... Droning on to them: "In the name of the Monolith...", so I ran the opposite way... and literally half an hour later we're fighting off fifty or so zombies. So there you have it. I found a couple stashes on the PDA, here and here. I cleared this one out on my way back, but I was too lazy to get the second one, plus I had no more room, and I've never even been to that area before.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_73"><text>They're saying there used to be piles of artefacts at the Agroprom, but I don't know if that's still the case... Alright, Marked One, stop by, if anything.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_81"><text>You got lucky. I advise that you don't go for stunts like that again. Look alive. See you later.</text></string>
<string id="freedom_7_dialog_82"><text>Okay, I'll stop by sometime.</text></string>
