<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<!--********************************-->
<!-- Sidorovich miniquest dialog start -->
<!--********************************-->
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_0"><text>Listen, you said you left something for me, right?</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_1"><text>Ah... Yeah, there is a bundle for you.</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_2"><text>That's great. Give it here.</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_3"><text>Your bundle, of course. I do not pretend to anything, do not think. Only I kept it in my place, right? Reliably, by the way. What if there is something bad? I, you know, have so little health left... \nIn short, I believe that a hundred rubles to me for storage is a fair price. I agree?</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_5"><text>How greedy you are! Hold, miser, "for storage"</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_6"><text>Everything is fair. Take it.</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_7"><text>Completely insolent? Either give me the bundle, or I will snitch anyone who needs to.</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_4"><text>Damn, with money strained. I'll pick up later.</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_8"><text>Here, get your precious bundle.</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_9"><text>Oh, you scared me. Who are you going to snitch?</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_10"><text>Beginners in the camp. Figs, they'll buy something from you after that.</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_11"><text>Military. Do you think they are not interested in a trader in the Zone?</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_12"><text>On your bald head. Do you want?</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_13"><text>I have friends. Very influential stalkers, by the way...</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_14"><text>If they don’t buy these, others will buy in a couple of days. This is the Zone.\nThey won’t be able to get back - soldiers are at the checkpoint, to go deeper into the air - equipment is needed, weapons. And where will you get it, if not from me? \nSo, threaten someone else, understand?</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_15"><text>Oh, I can’t! You can’t laugh like that... \nWhat do you think, who supplies me with equipment, writes off ammunition for sale? Does it forward artifacts to customers from the Zone? The military, on the contrary, is interested in my business. \nBut you go down to them, go down. I wonder if they’ll shoot you right away or put you in prison for life? And then do not worry about the package. Ha-ha.</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_16"><text>Damn, it's a pity for a hundred rubles - just say so. Everyone's so nervous - "on your bald head" right away...</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_17"><text>Remember: in the Zone, any friendship ends quickly when it comes to serious money. Yes, and what are your friends to me? Today there is, tomorrow they have already forgotten their name. They don’t live very long in the Zone, understand?</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_18"><text>In short, a hundred rubles for storage - and take your bundle.</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_19"><text>Thanks.</text></string>
<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_20"><text>Got it.</text></string>

<!--****************************-->
<!-- Barist Repair dialog start -->
<!--****************************-->
<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_0"><text>At you left something for me, right?</text></string>
<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_1"><text>Yes, a small bundle. It lies to itself, does not take up much space... I almost forgot about it. What do you need him for?</text></string>
<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_2"><text>Yes, I need it.</text></string>
<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_3"><text>Here, take it.</text></string>
<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_4"><text>Thanks.</text></string>
<!--********************-->
<!-- miniquest dialogs end -->
<!--********************-->

</string_table>