<!-- ;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;
;	 ,,,,,      ,,,,,,,    ,,,,,,_  ,,,,,,,,  ,,,,,,   
;       MMMMM1     M0MMMM&    MMMMM@'  MMMMMM0"  MMMM0!   
;       4MMMM#      ^MMMMMr   MMMMMf    #MMMM&    B0'     
;      &]MMMMMc      #MMMM# ] MMMMMf    #MMMM&   j#       
;      M 0MMMM&       MMMMML# MMMMMf    #MMMM&  pM&       
;     pY 4MMMMM     ] #MMMMM# MMMMMf    #MMMM& pMMMt      
;     M   MMMMMc    ]& MMMMMf MMMMMf    #MMMM&]MMMM0      
;    ]#   0MMMM&    ]M #MMMM  MMMMMf    #MMMM& MMMMM&     
;    QfjMMMMMMMM    ]M  MMMf  MMMMMf    #MMMM& 4MMMMM     
;   _M    "MMMMMf   ]M  BMM   MMMMMf    #MMMM&  MMMMM&    
;  _Q#     MMMMM&   jMg  M8  _MMMMMf    BMMMM&  jMMMMM,   
; 4MMMM   #MMMMMM# 0MMM& B  ]MMMMMMM&  0MMMMMM&]MMMMMMMt  
;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;

-->


<string id="amk_metka"><text>GPS-beacon</text></string>
<string id="amk_metka_s"><text>GPS-beacon</text></string>
<string id="enc_amk_metka"><text>GPS-beacon. He appeared in the Zone not so long ago, but enjoys wildly popularity due to its versatility and reasonable price. Initially, a prototype was brought into the territory of "Duty" to demonstrate and conclude a deal for the supply of large quantities of such beacons. However, the "accidental" loss of the test version on the eve of the meeting of representatives of both sides gave a deep crack in relations with the supplier. Long and mutually beneficial relations between Voronin and Sakharov came in handy here, and with the help of a local dealer, a prototype of the lighthouse fell into the hands of scientists at the field laboratory in Yantar. There he was modernized, and also put on mass production for the needs of all the afflicted. The original version was not preserved due to direct modernization of the prototype. The upgraded version differs in a positive way in that it allows you to put a digital signature on the beacon (Cyrillic, unfortunately, is not supported) and synchronize it with the owner’s PDA. Based on studies of the system of protection against psi effects, scientists have achieved that the beacon does not interfere, and detection by an outsider is almost impossible. Given the fact that the GPS-beacon is produced by Sakharov’s own laboratory, the scientist’s prices are more reasonable than those of the resellers.</text></string>